My name is Dalton Russell.
我的名字是道頓羅素
Pay strict attention to what l say
請仔細聽我說的話
because l choose my words carefully and l never repeat myself.
因為我要說的話很重要 而且不會重覆一次
l've told you my name. That's the ''who.''
我說出了名字，那是我的身份
The ''where'' could most readily be described as a prison cell.
我在的地方可以形容為囚房
DALTON: But there's a vast difference
但是被困在一個小囚房
between being stuck in a tiny cell and being in prison.
和坐牢有很大的不同
The ''what'' is easy.
我做了什麼事很容易解釋
Recently l planned and set in motion events to execute the perfect bank robbery.
最近我策劃並執行一起 完美的銀行搶案
That's also the ''when.''
我也說出了時間
As for the ''why,'' beyond the obvious financial motivation,
至於為什麼，除了很明顯的財務動機
it's exceedingly simple.
原因其實非常簡單
Because l can.
因為我辦得到
Which leaves us only with the ''how.''
現在只剩下我是怎麼辦到的
And therein, as the Bard would tell us,
就像大文豪莎士比亞說的
lies the rub.
這就耐人尋味了
So, your mother tells me about
你媽告訴我說
a certain young lady who's helping you with the Triborough Bridge project?
有位小姐在幫你做學校作業
-Okay? -All right, okay.
-好嗎？ -好的
He's crazy.
他瘋了
-Now? On 51st? 50... -CHAlM: Yeah, that's where he is right now.
-哪裡？51街嗎？ -對，他現在還住在那裡
He's on 40, he... No, he's still on 47th Street, but it's a much smaller space.
不，他還在47街，不過地方比較小
HAMMOND: What do l have to...
我要怎樣…
Yeah, we'll get lobster. l'll put it on Mr. Ansinori's card.
咱們去吃龍蝦，刷安先生的卡
Whatever. lt's a meeting with one of his clients or something.
無所謂，反正他要去見客戶
Because it's been like over a year now. Yeah.
這一年來都是這樣
l want to snap this guy's neck, l swear to God.
我好想掐斷這傢伙的脖子
NANCY: So what?
又怎樣？
So what? They're flowers. They could've been to his grandmother.
只是花嘛，也許是送他阿嬤的
They could've been to me. lt's my birthday, so...
也許是送我的，今天我生日
Okay, so maybe it's a client's.
好啦，搞不好是送客戶啦
Okay. This is funny.
這有夠好笑
l got this guy in front of me that thinks l don't see him looking at me.
這傢伙以為我沒看到他在瞄我
Fantastic. God damn it.
這下好了，真討厭
-Excuse me. -Yeah.
-對不起 -是
Can you lower your voice just a little bit, please?
請你小聲一點
You're getting a little loud on your phone. Please.
你講手機太大聲了
Yeah. Fine.
好啦
l don't want you disturbing the other customers.
你干擾到其他客戶
-Sorry. -All right?
-對不起 -好嗎？
-Yeah, you got it. -Thank you.
-好 -謝謝
lt was a security guy.
臭警衛
l didn't know l was in a library. lt's a fucking bank.
這又不是圖書館，這是銀行耶
Manhattan Trust.
曼哈頓信託銀行
...from Yale. And this fucking rich prick l work for.
我替有錢的混蛋工作
Thank you.
謝謝
Excuse me. Sir?
對不起，先生
DALTON: Easy.
別亂來
Everybody get down on the fucking floor! Now!
大家給我趴在地上！快點！
STEVE-O: Get down on the ground!
趴下來！
DALTON: You have four seconds! Anyone still standing gets shot!
我數到四！不然就吃子彈！
One! Two! Three!
一！二！三！
STEVE-O: Back away from that counter! Get your hand away from that button!
離開櫃檯！別碰按鈕！
Put your hands on the floor! Now!
手放在地上！
Oh... What the... What is this?
搞什麼？
-Todd, what are we gonna do? -What the fuck do you want me to do?
-怎麼辦？ -我怎麼知道
-STEVE-O: Keep your head down, fat man! -All right!
-低著頭，胖子 -好啦
DALTON: Get your fucking face on the floor!
乖乖趴在地上
You get the same treatment as everyone else, Rabbi.
你跟大家一樣，猶太教士
Get down.
趴下來
Now, my friends and l are making
我們打算
a very large withdrawal from this bank.
提領一大筆錢
Anybody gets in our way gets a bullet in the brain.
誰敢擋路，腦袋就會被轟掉
Lie down, old man! Put your fucking hands down!
趴下來，手放下來
-DALTON: Get your face on the floor. -MAN: All right, l'm down! l'm down!
-臉朝下 -好，我已經趴下來了
Hey, Officer, there's smoke coming out of there.
警官，那裡在冒煙
Possible 10-30. Manhattan Trust. 20 Exchange Place.
曼哈頓信託銀行有狀況 交易街20號
l have got hostages.
我挾持了人質
You fucking cops come near this door, l start killing people.
臭條子敢接近，我就殺人
l not fucking kidding, man.
我他媽的不是開玩笑
Central. Give me an 85.
勤務中心，請派支援
Back up, sir! Back up! You!
退後，退後，你！
-MAN: Shit! -Back up! Back up!
-靠 -退後
Stay around the corner!
留在轉角！
Central, give me an 85.
勤務中心，請派支援
Perp with a gun. Possible hostages.
嫌犯持槍，可能挾持人質
l repeat, possible hostages. 20 Exchange. Manhattan Trust.
重複一遍，嫌犯可能挾持人質 交易街20號，曼哈頓信託銀行
Baby, l'm fighting for my life over here.
我正面臨生死關頭耶
Keith, every time we have this conversation, it's the same thing.
基斯，你每次都找藉口
-''Not now.'' -Listen. Listen.
-拖時間 -聽好
Do you know what kind of thin ice l'm on right now
你知道我現在是怎樣的處境嗎？
with this check-cashing thing? They want to lock me up.
這張支票把我整慘了 我搞不好會坐牢
If this $140,000 doesn't show up somewhere soon,
14萬的支票找不到
-things gonna get rough for me. -But you didn't take it.
-我就慘了 -你又沒有拿
Of course l didn't take it, baby. lt's just some lying drug dealer
當然沒有，臭毒販為了脫罪
trying to save his own ass by fucking me over.
賴在我頭上
-Eventually, it'll go away. -Then what?
-我會想辦法搞定 -然後呢？
-What about us? -Then, you know, I'll make First Grade
-我們呢？ -我會升任高級警探
and we'll have enough money to buy a bigger place and then, you know...
然後我們就有錢能搬到大房子
Why we got to have this conversation every time your brother gets locked up
你老弟每次坐牢或偷車
-or gets caught stealing a car? -He's the only family l've got.
-我們都要談這件事嗎？ -他是我唯一的家人
All right, l'm sorry, baby. You okay?
對不起啦
-You still love me? -l'm sorry, too.
-你還愛我嗎？ -我也對不起
-l love you, baby.
-我愛你，寶貝
All right. Big Willie and the twins for you when l get home.
我會帶一鳥二石回家
-l got the handcuffs. -l got the gun.
-我會帶手銬 -我也會帶手槍
Bye, Big Daddy.
拜了，寶貝
-Big Willie and the twins, huh? -That's correct.
-一鳥二石？ -沒錯
Her lowlife brother, he's got three priors, one for armed robbery.
她老弟有三次前科，一次是持械搶劫
1 7-year-old high-school dropout. Doesn't have an honest bone in his body
高中沒念完，又笨又沒出息
and he's too fucking stupid to amount to anything. Even as a criminal.
連幹壞事都笨到被逮到
-Can't you get rid of him? -l could, couldn't l?
-你不如把他趕走 -對哦，不行啦
No, she loves him. What am l gonna do? Put him out in the street?
她很疼他，趕也趕不走
-How's he feel about you? -Oh, he's thrilled.
-他喜歡你嗎？ -愛得要命
To have a detective sleeping in the next room,
老姐在隔壁房間
banging his sister. Then she tries to bring it all back on me.
和警探嘿咻，她每次都怪我
You know, ''lf we had a bigger place, we wouldn't have this problem.''
有錢住大房子就不是問題
Of course, if we got married then things would be different.
如果我們結婚，就另當別論
-And what's wrong with that? -A wedding. Furniture. Kids.
-結婚有什麼不好？ -籌備婚禮、佈置房子、生小孩
You know what a diamond ring costs?
鑽戒很貴耶
-Come on, man. You've been married. -Please. l was 21 .
-你不是結過婚嗎？ -當年我才21歲
-Yeah, but you give her a ring? -Yeah, but she won't call me back.
-你有送她鑽戒嗎？ -有，但她拿了就跑了
-You guys cops? -Oh, shit! He made us!
-你們是警察嗎？ -靠，被他認出來了
Christmas came early for you this year.
今年耶誕節提早到來
Bank robbery. Hostage situation. 20 Exchange Place.
銀行搶案，人質危機，交易街20號
-What? -Grossman's on vacation. You're up.
-什麼？ -高警探休假，你上場
What about the Madrugada thing? The check-cashing thing?
支票不見那件事
-l thought l was in the doghouse. -l just threw you a bone.
-我還沒洗脫嫌疑耶 -我給你機會將功贖罪
As far as l'm concerned, you still work here,
你現在還在工作崗位上
-but if you don't think you're ready... -No, no, he's ready!
-如果你沒準備好… -他準備好了
Oh, good. Good.
很好
l'm giving you a break, here. Don't make me look like a fool.
這次我罩你，別給我凸槌
-This is it, baby. The show! -Yeah.
-棒呆了，好戲上場 -是啊
You got the call, man. God damn!
你能好好表現了
l guess l should be happy. l might get to put off l.A.B.
是啊，暫時能擺脫風紀組
Here's all you need to know. You walk in unarmed.
你只要記得一件事
Head bad guy puts a gun to your head and makes you get on your knees.
手無寸鐵走進去面對搶匪首領
You look around. There are five armed men pointing Uzis at you.
五個手下拿著衝鋒鎗指著你
Just picture them in their underwear.
然後想像他們穿內衣褲的樣子
How about orange jumpsuits and shackles?
或是想像他們穿囚衣戴手銬
-There you go, Keith. You can do this, man. -Look out, bad guys. Here l come.
-這就對了，你行的 -大壞蛋，我來也
COP: Get back around the corner! Get back!
退到轉角！退後！
l told you, move it! Move it!
我叫你們退後！
Get those people back! Get them the hell out of here!
把這些閒雜人等趕走！
All right, guys, as soon as we pull up, l want everybody out.
一到了就下車，上吧
The second floor window. Now.
二樓窗口
-Let them in there! -Let's go! Go now!
-讓他們進去！ -上吧！
Sarge, what do you got?
什麼狀況？
l got a perp in the bank. Possible hostage situation.
搶匪在銀行，可能有人質
Who's on today? Who's your boss?
今天誰指揮？
-Sergeant Hernandez. l'll get him over here. -Get him down here.
-何警官 -把他找來
-Sergeant Hernandez, you on the air? -On the air. Go.
-何警官？ -說吧
Sarge, l got Sergeant Collins over here. He called this in.
柯巡警報的案
Can you come over to the other side?
請你過來
Redirect, on my way. Let's go.
馬上來，上吧
COP 1 : Back up! Go around, around the corner.
支援！走邊邊
COP 1 : Pull back. Pull it back. COP 2: We got to keep this secure.
-撤退 -確保這裡安全
-Collins? What you got? -Hernandez.
-柯巡警，什麼狀況？ -何警官
l got a perp inside with a gun. He claims he's got some hostages in there.
搶匪持槍，他說有人質
Everyone, heads up! Let's clear the way!
讓出一條路
Let's go. Set them up. All right.
上吧，拉起拒馬
We've got it under control.
一切都在控制之下
Step back, please!
請退後
-Step back! -Get back! Thank you.
-退後 -回來，謝謝
There's nothing going on.
這裡沒什麼好看的
You'll see it on the news tonight.
你們今晚就會看到新聞了
Step back, please.
請退後
Mr. Case?
寇先生？
Oh, good morning, Katherine. What can l do for you?
早安，凱薩琳，有什麼事？
Sir, there's a robbery in progress at one of our branches.
有一間分行發生搶案
Oh, my.
天啊
-Has anybody been hurt? -l don't think so, but there are hostages.
-有人受傷嗎？ -沒有，不過有人質
Oh, how awful.
真糟糕
-Which branch is it? -Number 32. 20 Exchange Place.
-哪一間分行？ -32分行，交易街20號
-Which one? -20 Exchange Place.
-哪一間？ -交易街20號
Thank you, Katherine.
謝謝你，凱薩琳
l'm sorry, Mr. Case.
很遺憾
Oh, dear God.
天啊
Get these people out of here. Come on, open these gates. Back up.
把路人趕走，拉開拒馬
Up on the sidewalk. Come on in.
進來吧
Sergeant Collins, first on scene. Are you the hostage negotiator?
我是柯巡警，你是談判專家？
That's right. Detective Frazier. This is Detective Mitchell. What do you got?
對，費警探，這是米警探 什麼狀況？
Not much. Saw the bank was filled with smoke.
銀行煙霧瀰漫
The door was locked. l tried to take a look inside
大門鎖住，我探頭進去
and one of the gunmen opens the door, sticks a .357 in my face,
搶匪打開大門，拿點357手槍指住我
screaming in some foreign accent about killing hostages.
用外國口音說要殺死人質
-See any other gunmen? -No, sir. l couldn't see anything at all.
-看到其他嫌犯嗎？ -沒，什麼都看不到
-You hear anything inside? -No, sir,
-聽到什麼嗎？ -也沒
but with that .357 sticking in my face, l can't really be sure. l'm sorry.
他拿著槍指住我 我腦袋一片空白，對不起
Okay.
好吧
Good, good. Good, good, good, good. You did a good job, Sergeant.
很好，你做得很好
You ever had a gun stuck in your face before?
有人拿槍指過你嗎？
-Yeah, once. -Really?
-有一次 -真的？
Yeah, by a 1 2-year-old.
12歲的小子
-What was that like? -Not one of my better days.
-那次感覺怎樣？ -不是很好的經驗
l bet. All right, well, look.
那是一定的
As soon as we get this thing cleared up, we'll cut you loose, all right?
把事情搞清楚你就能回家
lf you don't mind, l'd rather hang around a while,
你不介意的話，我想留下來
at least until we make contact.
至少等到跟嫌犯有接觸後
That's what l like to hear, Sergeant.
這樣最好
What? Come on. Why you doing this? Why you doing this to me?
拜託，你幹嘛這麼做？
Pop, what's going on? Yo.
爸，怎麼回事？
STEVlE: All bank employees, raise your hands!
銀行職員舉手
Bank employees, this side! Everyone else, over there!
銀行職員到這邊，其他人到那邊
Now, l need everybody to take your cell phones and your keys
我要每個人把手機和鑰匙
out of your pockets and handbags and hold them in the air.
從口袋和皮包裡拿出來舉高
-What's your name? -Peter.
-你叫什麼？ -彼得
-Peter what? -Peter Hammond.
-彼得什麼？ -彼得韓蒙
-Where's your cell phone, Peter Hammond? -l left it at home.
-你的手機呢？ -留在家裡
Peter, think very carefully about how you answer the next question
我下一個問題你要好好回答
because if you get it wrong, your headstone will read,
答錯了你的墓碑銘會寫…
''Here lies Peter Hammond, hero,
大英雄彼得韓蒙英年早逝
''who valiantly attempted to prevent a brilliant bank robbery
他試圖阻止一場銀行搶案
''by trying to hide his cellular phone,
把手機藏起來
''but wound up getting shot in the fucking head.''
「結果被一槍轟掉腦袋」
Now, Peter Hammond,
彼得
where is your cell phone?
你的手機呢？
l'm telling you, l did. l left it at home.
我說過，我留在家裡
Okay, l fucked up. l'm sorry. Please.
我不該說謊，對不起
DALTON: Hey. Don't worry about it.
沒關係
Just let me talk to you! Please, please, listen to me.
拜託，聽我說
Let me explain.
讓我解釋
Help! Help me.
救命啊！
Stop!
住手！
Anyone else here smarter than me?
還有人自以為比我聰明嗎？
-And you are? -Vikram Walia.
-你叫什麼？ -威克姆瓦裡
Vikram Walia. Thanks, Vikram.
謝了，威克姆
BRlAN: Hey, mister.
先生
Keep it.
留著吧
Men here. Women here.
男人，這邊，女人，這邊
Move!
快點
l need all of you to strip down to your underwear.
全身脫光，只剩內衣褲
Lady?
女士
Believe me. This is the only situation where l'd ask you to do this.
相信我，平常我不會想看你的脫衣秀
-But take off your fucking clothes. -No.
-快給我脫衣服 -不
You should be ashamed of yourself.
你真不要臉
What's with you mishegoyim?
你是有毛病嗎？
Go ahead. Make my day.
有種就動手呀
-Take your fucking clothes off, lady. -No!
-把衣服給我脫掉 -不要！
Stevie?
史蒂威
Let's go!
走吧
Now, l need all of you
現在，我要你們全部
to put on one of these suits and these masks.
穿上這些衣服，戴上面罩
I'm Shon Gables, with CBS 2 News, outside Manhattan Trust Bank,
這是CBS記者香恩 我正在曼哈頓信託銀行外面
where we have just been told by investigators,
警方表示
the bank has been robbed.
銀行遭到搶劫
The suspect or possible suspects are inside,
嫌犯挾持人質
holed up with an unknown number of hostages.
人數不明
-Captain Darius? -Yeah.
-戴隊長？ -對
l'm Detective Frazier. This is Detective Mitchell.
我是費警探，這是米警探
Hey.
嘿
You may remember, we worked that hospital thing on 93rd,
我受訓時和你處理過
during my training?
人質事件
Oh, yeah. That was a real shame.
對，那次很遺憾
Yeah, it was. lt was.
是的
So, what do we got?
什麼狀況？
l got an unknown number of suspects and an unknown number of hostages,
搶匪和人質人數不明
and a bank, and about a million spectators, and l can't see shit inside there,
卻有一百萬個圍觀民眾 銀行啥都看不見
-so l'm kind of busy. -l understand.
-我很忙 -我瞭解
The way this works, Mr. Frazier, is l deal with Mr. Grossman.
我只跟高先生合作
So if you need anything, you can speak with him, okay?
有事請去找他，好嗎？
No, it's not okay, Captain.
不好，隊長
Detective Grossman is away on vacation,
高警探在休假
so Detective Frazier is the big dick today, all right?
今天費警探當家作主
Now, if you need anything, you can speak to me, all right?
你有事請來找我，行嗎？
l guess it'll have to be.
只好這樣吧
That's the way it's gonna be. You got vests for us?
沒錯，防彈背心？
-Berk! -BERK: Yo!
-小珀 -有
-Get these guys some vests! -Okay.
-給他們防彈背心 -好
-And check them into the command log.
-幫他們登記
You know what? l'm gonna get out of your hair
我們先讓你
and let you get control of this crime scene, okay?
掌握犯罪現場
You'll let me know when you're ready with a detailed briefing?
準備好了再通知我
-Okay. -We're gonna take a walk down to the diner.
-好 -我們要去小館子
Don't go in the bank without calling us first, all right? Okay?
行動之前先通知我們
-All right. -Good to see you, Captain.
-沒問題 -很高興見到你
Shouldn't we be in there?
我們不留在那兒嗎？
Let's give him some time. See what he does. Come on.
給他點時間，看他怎麼做
Until he secures his position and gets the physical layout,
他沒佈署好前
he'll only dump on us.
只會向我們發飆
lf the show starts, he'll call us. Trust me. l've seen him work.
行動之前他一定會通知我 相信我，我知道他會
Your call, Keith.
你做主
Can you get that for me? l guess it is, isn't it?
麻煩你
That's the one thing l learned from Grossman,
我一定要強勢一點
is these guys don't have much respect for what we do.
因為這些人不信談判這一套
-How do you mean? -Well, to them it's a tactical situation.
-怎麼說？ -他們只會硬著來蠻幹
Us being here means there's a mental side to it that they don't get.
完全不懂談判心理戰術
-Told you, you could handle this. -Yeah.
-我就說你一定行 -對
l keep waiting for someone higher up on the food chain to show up and say,
我一直在等上級命令我
''Here's what we do.''
「怎麼做」
What happened at the hospital?
上次人質事件怎麼回事？
Guy shot himself, shot his girlfriend. Thank you.
嫌犯殺死女友後自殺
l told you, l've got
我說過，我有…
a heart condition.
心臟病
Get up.
起來
HERNANDEZ: Put down your fucking weapons!
把槍放下
-Don't move! Don't move! -Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
-別動 -別開槍
-Don't move! Don't move! Come here! -l haven't got...
-別動，過來！ -我還沒…
-Come here, come here, come here! -l work in the bank!
-過來！ -我在銀行上班
On your knees! Down on your knees now!
跪下來！
-They sent me out here! -Now!
-他們派我出來 -現在
-He said stay away! -Cuff him.
-他叫你們離遠一點 -戴上手銬
lf you come near the bank, he'll throw out two dead bodies!
不然就會丟出兩具屍體
-Who said this? Who? -l don't know who!
-誰說的？ -我不認識！
The guy with the big fucking gun!
拿著好大一把槍的…
-That's who! -All right, get on your feet. Let's go.
-傢伙說的 -好，起來，走吧
-There's four of them in there! -Come on.
-一共有四個人 -來吧
Christ!
天啊
-Calm down! -Let's go!
-冷靜點 -走吧
-Am l gonna be on TV? -Yeah. A big star. Let's go. Come on.
-我會上電視嗎？ -會啦，大明星，走吧
Was it a time when l thought l might not see my family again? Yeah.
我有沒有想過不能再見到家人？
Yeah, l thought about it. l mean, at first, l wasn't...
當然有想過
lt was too much to think about at that point.
一開始我被槍指住完全呆掉
You know, with a gun in your face, but after a while l...
過了一會兒…
You know, l thought about...
我才想到…
Yeah.
嗯…
My wife, you know, not seeing my wife again.
也許不能再見到我老婆小孩
My kids. l got a 10-year-old son, 1 7-year-old daughter.
我有一個十歲大的兒子 一個十七歲大的女兒
Yeah, l thought about it, man. What do you think?
我當然會想到他們
Those are my babies.
他們是我的心肝寶貝
DALTON: Beautiful.
太完美了
Go ahead.
開始吧
Miss White, l want you to rest assured
魏小姐，請你放心
my only intention is to spend time in your wonderful city
我只想住在這個美好城市
and to enjoy all that it has to offer.
好好地享受生活
And no business with your uncle?
你沒跟你叔叔做生意？
ln truth, l have very little to do with him these days.
我跟他沒什麼關係
l'm told you haven't seen him in nine years. ls that right?
你也有九年沒見過他了？
-You are extremely well informed. -l have to be. Yes?
-你的消息很靈通 -這是一定要的，是的？
l have a Mr. Arthur Case on the phone for you.
寇亞瑟先生來電
We'll need to end this here.
今天就到此結束
l'm gonna need a copy of your purchase agreement,
我需要購買協議書
your mortgage application, and the other documentation,
和房貸申請表
-and l'll be in touch. -Thank you, Miss White.
-保持聯絡 -謝謝你，魏小姐
Right this way, sir.
這裡請
Arthur Case? You sure?
寇亞瑟？你確定？
-That's what he said. -He said his name, just like that?
-他是這麼說 -是他本人說的
lt wasn't his secretary saying he was on the line?
不是秘書？
-No, ma'am. -All right. Put him through.
-沒錯 -接過來
Okay.
好
-This is Madeleine White. -Miss White, I'm Arthur Case.
-我是麥德琳魏特 -我是寇亞瑟
Oh, good morning, Mr. Case.
早安
-Have we met formally? -No, sir, I don't believe we have.
-我們正式見過面嗎？ -應該沒有吧
Yet, you're always turning up
我在南漢普敦的派對
at my July 4th parties in Southampton.
你都有去
Yes, we know some of the same people.
是的，我們有相同的朋友
lt seems.
我猜是吧
l'll come right to the point.
我就直話直說了
l have a small problem which requires someone
我有一件麻煩事
with very special skills and complete discretion.
需要能力強，能保密的人處理
Are you such a person or have l been misinformed?
你是這個人嗎？還是誤傳的？
Go on.
請繼續說
Can l pick you up in front of your office building in five minutes?
我五分鐘後去接你
-l'll be downstairs. -Thank you.
-我會在樓下等你 -謝謝
They had a kind of genius plan
他們計劃周詳、大費周章
for throwing us out of whack
把我們耍得團團轉
and depriving us of any kind of way of controlling ourselves.
讓我們完全搞不清狀況
They were... They were very
他們的態度非常…
insistent, and yet, strangely detached.
強硬，不過感覺卻很疏離
All l know is that they called each other a variation of Steve.
他們互相稱呼史蒂夫小名
Steven, Steve-O, Stevie.
史蒂芬、史蒂佛、史蒂威
And they called you what?
他們怎麼稱呼你？
They didn't call me anything. They just told me...
沒有，他們只…
You're lying to me. Tell me the truth, now. You're lying to me.
你在說謊，老實說
Tell me the... Look at me and tell me the truth.
看著我說實話
They had AK-47 s out. Four of them.
他們四個都有AK-47衝鋒鎗耶
-You know a lot about guns. -No.
-你是槍械專家嗎？ -不是
-l don't know anything about guns, except... -But you know they had an AK-47.
-我對槍一點都不懂 -你就認得AK-47衝鋒鎗
-Everybody knows what an AK-47 is. -Everybody?
-每個人都認得吧 -每個人？
Anybody who's ever watched a decent action movie would.
每個看過動作片的人都認得
-You ever rob a bank before? -Are you kidding?
-你搶過銀行嗎？ -開什麼玩笑？
Me rob a bank? No.
我才沒有咧
-Never stole a dollar? -Never.
-你沒偷過錢嗎？ -沒有
-Never? -Not ever.
-從來沒有？ -一次也沒有
-You know what? -That one time. That one time, that one time.
-其實咧 -一定有過一次
l stole a nickel from my grandmother's pocketbook once.
我從我外婆的皮包偷過五角
She was Polish.
她是波蘭人
l used to go up to her and say, ''Mama, toh nicklah, toh nicklah. ''
我都跟她說…
One day, l opened her pocketbook and there was a nickel.
有一天我打開她皮包看到五角
l took it.
於是就拿走
That was the only thing l ever took.
我只拿走五角硬幣
Look, Detective, l didn't mean to give you a hard time back there.
我剛才不是故意找你碴
Forget about it. What's the story, Captain?
算了，情況如何？
Well, the hostage they let go was Herman Gluck, 73.
被放的人質是古赫蒙，73歲
He was having chest pains. Paramedics have him.
他的胸口疼痛 醫務人員正在幫他檢查
They told him to say that if any cops came near the door,
他說警方如果敢靠近大門
they'd throw out two dead bodies.
他們就會丟出兩具屍體
He thinks there's four perps. Says they came in dressed as painters.
他認為有四名搶匪 扮成油漆工走進銀行
There's a video system in the bank.
銀行有監視系統
We're working on getting a download
我們正在下載
from Manhattan Trust's central security office, but it'll take a while.
監視器畫面，不過要花點時間
We got the block locked up. l got men in the windows.
整條街封鎖，狙擊手守在窗口
We're checking on the sewers with D.E.P.
我們也在檢查下水道出口
What about the phones?
電話呢？
Cut and diverted into M.C.C. We're the only ones they're gonna call.
全都轉到這裡來 他們只能打給我們
Cell phones are monitored and we can jam the air whenever you say.
手機已受到監控 隨時可以攔截通話訊號
But we like to leave it clear in case a hostage is able to get through,
也許人質會打手機求救
but so far nothing.
目前沒有任何消息
-91 1? -lt's up on the screen.
-119報案中心呢？ -在螢幕上
Any call about a bank gets routed straight to us.
所有相關報案電話都會轉過來
Well, that's my end of it, Detective.
這就是目前的狀況
Yeah.
好
Yeah, l'm not calling them yet.
我還不要打給他們
Beg your pardon?
什麼？
Doesn't feel right yet, you know what l mean?
時機還不對
l'm not gonna call him and ask what l can do for him.
我不想先問他需要什麼
Let's see what he does.
我要看他下一步做什麼
Your call.
你做主
Now, Mr. Case, why don't you let me explain to you how l work?
讓我解釋我的做事方式
Please. That would be nice.
請說吧
Well, you say that there are family heirlooms inside your safety deposit box.
你說你的保險箱有傳家之寶
That's fine.
沒問題
But in my experience, people like you have people working for them
不過以我的經驗，你這種人通常有人
that handle these kinds of things.
處理這種事
And when they can't, well, they don't call me.
不會親自打電話給我
Their people call me.
而是請親信打給我
So, immediately, l know that there's something in that box
所以你在保險箱放的東西
that you don't even want your closest aides to know about.
就連親信都不想讓他們知道
No problem with me.
這也沒問題
You tell me l don't need to know what's in that box and l don't need to know.
我不必知道保險箱裡有什麼
But if you tell me that it's a bunch of old baseball cards
不過如果你說是棒球卡
and l find out that it's the launch codes for a nuclear missile,
我卻發現是核彈發射密碼
then let's just say we no longer have an agreement.
那我們的協議就失效
-Have you finished? -Yes.
-你說完了嗎？ -說完了
What's inside that box, young lady,
保險箱裡的東西
has belonged to me since before you were born.
比你還要老
lt's very valuable and poses no danger whatsoever to anyone.
而且非常珍貴 對任何人不會造成危險
Except you.
除了你以外
Okay. Well, first, there are men with guns in there,
首先，銀行有持槍搶匪
so l can't guarantee any results. Agreed?
我沒辦法保證能進去，同意嗎？
-Of course. -All right.
-當然了 -好
Now, what makes you think that they want to rob your box?
你確定他們想搶你的保險箱？
l don't.
我不確定
Well, why don't you tell me how you would like this to end?
你希望達到什麼目的？
l'd prefer that nobody ever touch my safe deposit box.
我不要任何人動我的保險箱
Not them, not you, not the authorities.
你、搶匪或警方都不能動
And the sooner this situation ends, the happier l'll be.
這件事愈早收場我愈高興
-ls that specific enough for you? -No.
-我說的夠清楚吧？ -不夠
The contents of that box
保險箱裡的東西
are of great value to me.
對我很重要
So long as they remain my secret.
那是我的秘密
And if they're exposed?
如果這些秘密曝光？
l'll face some difficult questions.
我就會面對很多麻煩
-So, it stays locked or it disappears. -Precisely.
-最好鎖起來或消失不見 -沒錯
-Can you make that happen? -Yes.
-你辦得到嗎？ -辦得到
l hope so. l have to say, l can't help but be skeptical.
希望如此，老實說，我對你沒信心
Whoever gave you my number got the same deal.
我也幫過向你推薦我的人士
Clearly, they must have been satisfied.
很顯然他們對我很滿意
Steve?
史蒂夫？
lt's time for Steve-O.
這次是史帝佛
l came out here to take a look at the perimeter they laid down.
我出去勘察現場
Guess what l found?
你猜我發現什麼？
That hostage they let out said these guys came in dressed like painters, right?
人質說搶匪扮成油漆工
Yeah.
對
Probably stolen.
很可能是贓車
Have them run it and check it for prints.
請鑒識人員查指紋
-Everybody on? -Yep, l'm there.
-準備好了嗎？ -好了
-Sure you got the right number? -Absolutely.
-電話號碼對嗎？ -沒錯
Okay. Nothing yet.
沒人接
We got video.
調到監視畫面了
Let's have it.
放出來
FRAZlER: What happened to that camera right there?
攝影機怎麼了？
ROURKE: Wait. Hold on, hold on, hold on.
等等
FRAZlER: Yeah, there it is. That guy right there.
對，這裡，那傢伙
lt's like he blinds the camera with the flashlight.
用手電筒破壞攝影機
lt's weird, isn't it? lt's like nobody else sees it.
好奇怪耶，別人都沒看見
-You'd think it'd be pretty bright, huh? -lt could be infrared.
-閃光應該很亮才對 -可能是紅外線
-What's that? -lnfrared bulb.
-什麼？ -紅外線燈泡
See, humans can't see it, but a video camera will pick it up.
肉眼看不見，攝影機能接收
He could knock out the cameras without no one knowing.
他能神不知鬼不覺破壞攝影機
FRAZlER: Right, right, right, right.
對
ROURKE: He knocked out the cameras about 10:00.
那是早上十點的事
So, for approximately two minutes,
整整有兩分鐘
we got no evidence of people leaving or entering the bank. That's great.
不知道有誰進出銀行
MlTCHELL: Miriam, how long were you there before it began?
瑪莉蓮，事發前你在銀行多久？
lt was just a few minutes.
幾分鐘而已
Well, can you tell us what happened after the explosions and the smoke?
爆炸和冒煙之後發生什麼事？
They just told us to put our heads down. And then close our eyes.
他們叫我們趴下來，閉上眼睛
And then l just remember one of them
其中一個
telling the others to just go down and fix the cameras.
叫其他人搞定攝影機
-The video cameras? -I don't know.
-監視攝影機？ -我不知道
Anything else you want to share with us?
還有什麼嗎？
No, just...
沒了
-You sure? -Yeah, l...
-你確定？ -確定
Could you give us the names of the bank robbers, maybe?
請你招出搶匪的姓名
l'm just messing with you, sweetheart.
我在耍你啦
-You okay? -Thank you.
-沒事吧？ -謝謝你
Okay.
好
-lt was pretty awful. -Was it bad?
-好可怕哦 -很恐怖嗎？
l mean, they made us strip.
他們逼我們脫衣服
They made us take off our clothes.
逼我們把衣服全脫光
l don't understand why they had to do that.
我不知道為什麼
l really just thought...
我真的以為…
l thought l was gonna be killed.
我死定了
Well.
好了
-All right, my dear. -Okay.
-沒事了 -好
-l can go? -No.
-我能走了嗎？ -不能
-No? -No, you got to stay.
-不能？ -你得留下來
-You got to stay. -No, you can go.
-你可以走了
No, stay. No, go.
不行
Did you rob the bank?
銀行是你搶的嗎？
-You did. -Did you rob the bank?
-就是你 -是不是你？
-No. -You sure?
-不是 -你確定？
-BERK: There's movement at the front door. -Let's go.
-大門有動靜 -上吧
HERNANDEZ: Put down the fucking weapon! VlKRAM: Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
-把槍放下！ -別開槍
HERNANDEZ: Don't move! Don't move!
別動！別動！
COP: He's got a device on him there.
他身上有引爆裝置
l said put your hands on your head and get down on your fucking knees!
手放在頭後面，跪下來
and down on your knees now!
我叫你手放在頭後面，跪下來
COP: Hands are tied! HERNANDEZ: Hands are tied.
-他的手被綁住了
-Jesus, pat him down. -All right.
-搜他的身 -好
-VlKRAM: l'm one of the hostages! -Careful.
-我是人質 -小心
HERNANDEZ: Easy, be very careful, now. Easy.
-輕點，小心點 -我這裡無法瞄準他
SNlPER 2: l can see him. l got a clear shot. HERNANDEZ: Any weapons?
-我這裡可以 -有武器嗎？
-Who are you? -Vikram Walia. l work in the bank.
-你是誰？ -威克姆瓦裡，銀行職員
Okay. Vikram? ls this a bomb?
這是炸彈嗎？
-Oh, shit! A fucking Arab! -What? No. l'm a Sikh!
-靠，臭阿拉伯佬 -我是錫克教徒
-ls that a bomb? -No.
-那是炸彈嗎？ -不是
-Answer me, Vikram. ls this a bomb?
-說，這是炸彈嗎？ -才不是
-Are you booby-trapped? -No, fuck, no.
-這是陷阱嗎？ -不是
Okay, Vikram, l need you to relax.
威克姆，放輕鬆
-Jesus, give me a hand. -l don't know.
-幫我一下 -我不知道
SNlPER 1 : Just watch. There's a lot of movement in that bank.
銀行有動靜
-Team, take him down. -Mike, now, get him.
-把他壓住 -壓住他
What the fuck? Easy, easy.
搞什麼？輕點
Get off my... That's my turban. Get off. Easy.
我的頭巾，放開我
Get... My turban! Look, fuck, give my turban back!
把頭巾還給我
Come on, shut up. Relax.
閉嘴
What the fuck are you doing? Give me my turban back.
你在幹嘛？把頭巾還給我
-You can't fucking rip my turban. -Shut up, already.
-你們不能扯掉我的頭巾 -閉嘴
-What the fuck? -Come on, move it.
-搞什麼？ -快走
Get your fucking hands off me!
把手拿開
And the 1 1 :00 and 1 2:00...
十一點和十二點…
And don't forget about your 1 :00 with Chancellor Joel Klein.
你一點和柯喬伊有約
-Oh, Madge. What a day... -Your Honor.
-今天真忙 -市長
Madeleine! How are you?
麥德琳，你好
l'm just fine, but thank you for seeing me on such short notice.
謝謝你臨時抽空接見我
-Sure. Madge, are we through here? -Yes, Mr. Mayor.
-沒事了嗎？ -沒事了
This way, Miss White.
這裡請
l always have time to put on a tux and eat free food for a good cause.
我一向都很樂意參加慈善晚會
Who are we saving this week?
這星期又是什麼場合？
Well, l'm doing a round of support
我正在幫…
for the Joseph Freidkin Memorial Fund for Spinal Cord Research
裴氏脊髓研究紀念基金會籌備
and we're having our annual fundraiser next month.
募款晚會是下個月
lf you could attend, it would give us such a boost.
你大駕光臨能助益不少
lt would be my pleasure. ls there anything else l can do to...
我的榮幸，我還能幫什麼…
-What the fuck do you want? -A favor.
-你他媽的要什麼？ -幫一個忙
-No shit. Which kind? -The last one l'll ever ask of you.
-什麼樣的忙？ -我請你幫的最後一個忙
That's the kind l had in mind.
最好是這樣
You know about this hostage situation.
你知道人質危機事件
On my way. What's it to do with you?
這跟你有什麼關係？
All right, well, l need to keep an eye on it.
我要親自在場監督
So, l want you to bring me down there and tell whoever's in charge
我要你帶我去告訴指揮官
to extend me every courtesy.
讓我參與一切行動
You're out of your fucking mind.
你發瘋了
lf it was easy, it wouldn't square us, would it?
答應這件事，咱們就扯平
-lt's impossible. -Nothing's impossible.
-這是不可能的事 -天下無難事
You just have to call in a few markers, that's all.
一定有人欠你情
l may have to give out a few.
我恐怕會欠別人的情
Then that's exactly what you'll do.
那你也只好這麼做
You're a magnificent cunt.
你真是個難纏的婊子
Thank you.
多謝誇獎
It's been a very tense situation for several hours now.
對峙局勢持續了幾個小時
It's unclear how many hostages are inside
搶匪和人質的人數
and how many robbers police are dealing with.
仍然不明
Officials say this all started out as a robbery at Manhattan Trust,
警方只說一開始是搶案
but has turned into this hostage situation.
後來變成人質危機
Negotiators are here on the scene, working very hard
談判專家正在努力想辦法
and it's still unclear on any possible injuries.
但是仍不確定是否有人質受傷
Of course, we'll keep you up to date with the very latest
我們會向大家報告最新消息
and we will remain here on the scene as this all unfolds.
也會繼續在現場進行連線報導
That's the latest from here in lower Manhattan.
這是目前為止現場的最新消息
Reporting live, I'm Sandra Endo. Back to you.
我是記者遠籐珊卓
VlKRAM: ''Protect and serve'' my ass. Where's my turban?
人民保母個屁啦，我的頭巾呢？
l'm not talking to anybody without a turban.
沒有頭巾我什麼都不說
lt's part of my religion, to cover my head in respect to God. l'm a Sikh.
包頭巾是尊敬上帝 我是錫克教徒
MlTCHELL: Okay, we'll find your turban.
我們會找到頭巾
Not an Arab, by the way, like your cops called me outside.
警察罵我是臭阿拉伯人
Now, no, l don't think you heard that.
你一定是聽錯了
There was a lot going on. You were probably disoriented.
情況很混亂，你沒聽清楚
-l didn't hear that. -l heard what l heard.
-我就沒聽到 -我聽得很清楚
l'll give you all the information you want.
該說的我會說
l don't need this. l need my turban. lt's part of my religion.
我不要冰袋，我要頭巾
-We'll get you your turban. -We'll find it for you.
-我們會把頭巾還給你 -我們馬上就去找
No, no, no. Not ''get me.'' l want my turban now.
我現在就要
You just got to start thinking about the people inside the bank now.
你要替人質著想
lt's a dangerous situation.
現在情況危急
You got to start telling us about what's going on inside the bank.
告訴我們銀行發生什麼事
We can talk about this later. We'll get an officer to come down.
你被打的事以後再說
You can write a formal complaint.
你可以提出申訴
But for now, we got to deal with this situation.
現在先處理眼前的問題
First you beat me, and now you want my help.
你們先打我，然後要我幫忙
You need to start thinking about your coworkers.
你得替你的同事著想
l could apologize on behalf of the NYPD, but that was not us. We are detectives.
我可以替紐約警局向你道歉 但是罵你的人不是我們
-We're gonna try and find out... -What do you want to know?
-我們試著找出… -你們想知道什麼？
-How many were there? -l think there were about four.
-有幾名搶匪？ -四名
-How many hostages? -l don't know how many hostages, 20, 30.
-幾名人質？ -不知道，二、三十個
l'm fucking tired of this shit. What happened to my fucking civil rights?
我受夠了，我沒有人權嗎？
Why can't l go anywhere without being harassed?
我走到哪裡都被騷擾
l get thrown out of a bank. l'm a hostage. l get harassed.
我被挾持當人質、被騷擾
l go to the airport.
到機場搭飛機
l can't go through security without a ''random'' selection.
也一定會被警衛隨機搜身
Fucking random, my ass. l nearly lost my job...
去你的隨機啦
l bet you can get a cab, though.
你一定攔得到計程車
l guess that's one of the perks.
也只有這個好處
Put the ice on your face.
拿冰袋敷臉
FRAZlER: ''Two buses with full gas tanks. One jumbo jet with full gas tank
兩輛加滿油的巴士
''and pilots at JFK, parked at the end of runway. ''
「一架加滿油的客機和駕駛員」
They give us until 9.:00 pm to do this,
時限是晚上九點
then they kill one hostage every hour in front of TV cameras.
然後就每小時殺一名人質
''Bank is secured with Semtex. We will demonstrate if necessary.''
「銀行放置塑膠炸彈 有必要就會引爆」
-Whatever you do, don't give them a jet. -There's no plane. Maybe a bus. Maybe.
-別給他飛機 -沒有飛機，也許有巴士
Till l talk to them, they get nothing. Not even a cup of coffee.
他不肯談什麼都沒有 連一杯咖啡都不給
For now, we wait.
現在我們慢慢等
Let's let them wonder what we're doing, okay?
讓他們猜我們在幹嘛
Excuse me, Detectives. This is Arthur Case.
這位是寇亞瑟
-He's the... -l'm Chairman, Board of Directors.
-他是… -我是董事長
-Of the bank. You wanna talk to him? -Absolutely.
-銀行董事長，你要跟他談嗎？ -當然
Mr. Case, how are you? l'm Detective Frazier.
寇先生，你好，我是費警探
Anything in particular you think we should know?
你有什麼要告訴我們？
No. l just wondered if l might be of some assistance.
沒有，我只是想來幫忙
-Have they made any demands? -They want a jet.
-他們提出要求嗎？ -他們要一架噴射客機
Oh, l see.
我明白了
Would you like me to arrange one for you?
你們要我安排嗎？
l'm so sorry. l must have misunderstood.
很抱歉，我誤解了
That's quite all right, Mr. Case.
沒關係
Where can we reach you if we need anything?
有事的話要怎麼找你？
Well, those are my people in there, you know,
他們是我的員工
and l would like to stay here for a while. And l won't disturb you.
我想留下來，我不會礙事
CASE: l'll be very quiet right down... MlTCHELL: Sergeant Collins!
-我會很安靜 -柯巡警
Mr. Case, we'll try and keep you posted as best we can,
一有消息我們會通知你
but you're gonna have to excuse us for now, okay?
請你先離開
COLLlNS: Right this way, sir. FRAZlER: Thank you very much.
-這裡請 -謝謝
-Absolutely. -This way, sir.
-好 -這裡請
-FRAZlER: Thank you very much. -And thank you all so much.
-多謝了 -謝謝大家
-Thank you. -You're welcome.
-謝謝你 -不客氣
This way, sir.
這裡請
''Fifty hungry people need food now.''
「五十個人肚子餓要吃東西」
All right. Are we ready with the listening devices?
竊聽器準備好了嗎？
l'm gonna need 15 minutes once we get the food.
我需要15分鐘安裝
Pizza's the best. No sandwiches.
送披薩最好，不能給三明治
MlTCHELL: ls she for real? FRAZlER: Are you for real?
-她是說真的嗎？ -是嗎？
Well, if we send in, say, 10 pizzas boxes with transmitters,
十個披薩盒都裝上竊聽器
maybe we'll get some conversation if we give them something to group around.
就能聽到一群人交談
Give them each a sandwich, it's hit or miss.
三明治可以帶著走來走去
They can move around and l don't have 50 transmitters.
不過我可沒有五十個竊聽器
-What's this? -lt's a digital recorder.
-這是什麼？ -數位錄音筆
You click it, and it'll record for half an hour.
按一下就能錄半小時
-James Bond shit. -Well, you can get them on Amazon.
-007情報員用的玩意 -拍賣綱站就買得到
-You gonna ask for a hostage? -He already gave us one, didn't he?
-你要交換一個人質？ -他給我們一個了
l ask for another one, he says no, then what?
再要一個他一定會拒絕
No, he knows what he's doing.
他很清楚他在做什麼
He gave us a hostage. We'll give him some food.
給我們一個人質就能換吃的
l don't want to get caught bluffing this guy.
我不想虛張聲勢被他逮到
Fuck this shit. Look, they want to shoot me for taking off my mask, they can go ahead.
我不戴面罩，要殺要剮儘管來
Do you wanna get us all killed?
你想害死大家嗎？
You wanna relax? What the hell is the difference?
安啦，不會有事的
They're out there robbing the bank!
他們正在忙著搶銀行
-Can't you see they fucked him up? -Shut up.
-他被痛扁一頓耶 -閉嘴
You think they dressed us like this for fun, puneta?
我們穿成這樣不是為了好玩
-l have no idea -Please shut up.
-我搞不懂 -請閉嘴
...why they made us put on all of this crap.
他們幹嘛逼我們穿這玩意？
Probably so when the cops break in and try to rescue us
也許是讓警察分不出好人壞人
-we all get fucking shot. -Oh, my God!
-一古腦把我們都斃了 -天啊
lt's a great plan, but, no, thanks.
有夠天才，我才不上當
l told you to shut up! Leave him!
我叫你閉嘴！放開他！
No! Don't do this to me! Please, don't.
別這樣對我，求求你
l'll do as you say! No! Help! Help!
我會照你說的做！救命！
Please, don't! Don't!
求求你，不要
One guy did most of the talking.
其中一個發號施令
He told everyone else what to do.
其他人都聽他的
-So they were talking amongst themselves? -We couldn't hear them.
-他們會互相交談嗎？ -我聽不見
They had us in these rooms.
他們把我們關在房間
The doors were locked all the time.
房門關得緊緊的
We didn't know what they were doing.
根本不知道他們在幹嘛
-Did you hear anything they said? -l have problems with my hearing.
-你聽見什麼嗎？ -我的耳朵有毛病
-l see. -l wear hearing aids.
-原來如此 -我得戴助聽器
-Where are they? -They're in my ears.
-在哪兒？ -我耳朵裡頭
-Let's see. -Let me see them.
-拿出來 -給我看
-Yeah, let's take a look at them. -Yeah, it's a hearing aid.
-給我看，拿出來 -是助聽器沒錯
That's your other one, there?
那是另一個？
What's the red part, there? What does that do?
顏色怎麼不同？
They're different colors. You need two different...
顏色不同
And to distinguish right from left, also.
才能分辨左右
-Distinguish right from left? -Yeah.
-分辨左右 -對
Right from wrong.
或是對錯？
l don't understand.
我不明白
-Steve? -l'm sorry?
-史蒂夫？ -什麼？
-l didn't say anything. -Oh.
-我什麼也沒說 -噢
Steve. ls that your name? Steve?
你叫史蒂夫嗎？
Stevie? Steve-O?
史蒂威？史蒂佛？
-How much are they gonna pay you? -l'm sorry?
-他們要給你多少錢？ -什麼？
-You heard me. -No, l didn't.
-你聽見了 -我沒聽見
-How much are they going to pay you? -Who's gonna pay me?
-他們要給你多少錢？ -誰？
-Were you involved in this robbery? -Absolutely not.
-這起搶案你有份嗎？ -沒有
Were you involved in this situation?
這件事你有參一腳嗎？
-What situation? -Don't lie. Don't lie.
-什麼事？ -別說謊
lf he gives us a tip, l'm keeping it.
如果他給小費，我要留著
-Put that gun down! -Check that weapon!
-把槍放下 -看那把槍
All right, everybody, relax. Calm down. Calm down.
別緊張，冷靜點
Calm the fuck down!
給我冷靜點！
How you doing?
你好
l'm Detective Keith Frazier, Hostage Negotiation Team.
我是費警探，人質談判專家
How's it going?
你好嗎？
Okay. l hope the pizzas are okay. They might be a little cold.
披薩可以吧，已經涼了
Listen, you pick up the phone anytime you want.
只要拿起電話
lt's a direct line to me.
都能打給我
l would love to talk to you.
我想跟你談談
Nice talking to you.
很高興跟你聊天
Shit. Fucking Russians.
可惡，是臭俄國佬
Call Operations. See if they can get a Russian translator over here ASAP.
請總部派俄語翻譯來
DARlUS: And get some fucking body bags.
順便帶幾個屍袋來
l hope you know what you're doing.
你最好能搞定
Because if my guys got to shoot it out with those fucking savages...
要是我的手下得跟他們火拚…
Okay, okay, okay. Mitch?
好啦，米契
Check with either one of the hostages.
去問人質
Find out if they heard any Russian or Russian accents when they were in there.
有沒有聽到俄語或俄國口音
We'll be all right.
不會有事的
No!
不要
Down on the floor!
趴下來
Come on, sweetheart. Let's go. Let's go.
小妞，跟我走
Stop crying! Shut the fuck up!
別哭，給我閉嘴
Get in there! Sit down! Put your masks on!
進去，坐下來，戴上面罩
Come on, let's go. Come on, boobs.
走吧，波霸
-''Boobs''? Who the fuck you talking to? -Let's go. You heard me! Shut the fuck up!
-波霸？你說什麼？ -你聽到了，閉嘴
-Why? -Move that fat ass! Let's go! Come on!
-為什麼？ -快走，肥婆
''Fat ass''? Are you kidding me?
肥婆？你在說笑？
lf you don't shut the fuck up, l'm gonna put my foot up your fat ass!
閉嘴，小心我扁你
Put your masks on!
戴上面罩
Put your hands on the ground!
手放在地上
Okay, okay.
好，好
Masks on!
戴上面罩
Put your hands on the ground!
手放在地上
Come on, boobs, let's go.
走吧，波霸
Oh, shit. Sit down! Sit down!
坐下來
WlNG: She was on line in front of me.
她排在我前面
He was the teller on my line.
他是這一排的銀行行員
This guy was to my right and his kid was in front of him.
這傢伙在我右邊，他的兒子在他前面
He was playing with a video game.
他在打電動
l remember her.
我記得她
-Why do you remember her? -Great tits.
-為什麼？ -大咪咪
-You remember seeing any of them after? -Yeah, l saw her one time afterwards.
-後來你有看到他們嗎？ -我看到她一次
-How are you sure you saw her again? -l could see under the suit.
-你怎麼確定？ -波那麼大我不會認錯
Can't hide quality like that.
穿什麼都遮不住
This guy, he almost got us all killed.
這傢伙差點害死我們
How?
怎麼說？
They put eight or nine of us in an office for a while.
八、九個人被關在辦公室
This guy took off his mask and was talking like he wasn't afraid.
這傢伙耍狠不戴面罩 然後還嗆聲說…
''l don't have to wear this damn mask,'' you know?
「我才不戴這個臭面罩咧」
So, they come in, pull him out of the room and smack him around a little.
他們把他拖出去毒打一頓
-You see him again after that? -No.
-你有再看到他嗎？ -沒
-Was he okay? -Seemed fine.
-他沒事吧？ -看起來沒事
-You recognize anyone else from that room? -l can't be sure about the others.
-你認得其他人嗎？ -我不確定
No one?
一個都不認得？
-Why don't you keep looking? -You know, l was terrified.
-繼續看 -當時我嚇個半死
What about before it began?
案發之前
You didn't look around while you were waiting in line?
排隊的時候呢？
l was talking to my girlfriend on the phone.
我在跟朋友講電話
You wanna take another picture?
你想再替我拍一張嗎？
l could bend over and pick up a pencil.
我可以彎下身撿鉛筆
NANCY: Whatever.
隨你們便
This guy.
這傢伙
Asshole.
大爛人
What the fuck? This ain't Russian.
搞什麼，這不是俄語
No? What the hell is it?
那這是什麼語言？
lt's not Polish. Not Hungarian.
不是波蘭話，不是匈牙利話
Bulgarian, maybe.
也許是保加利亞話
lt's Central European. Sort of.
應該算是中歐語言吧
That's it? l mean, you're the language expert.
你是語言專家耶
What? No.
才不是咧
-What do you think? -Well, okay.
-你覺得怎樣？ -我想…
Well, this is New York City.
這是紐約
Somebody on the street must know what it is.
哪一國人都有
Probably the hot-dog man.
熱狗小販一定知道
Berk, play that over the speaker for me. Excuse me.
用喇叭放出來，借過
Excuse me!
對不起
Does anybody know what language they're speaking? Anybody?
有人知道這是什麼語言嗎？
KEVlN: Yo, my man.
我知道
Hey, Phil, let that guy through. Come on.
讓這傢伙過來
-You know what language they're speaking? -Yeah, they're speaking Albanian.
-你知道他們在講什麼話？ -對，阿爾巴尼亞語
-Albanian? -Albanian. From Albania.
-阿爾巴尼亞語？ -阿爾巴尼亞的阿爾巴尼亞語
What am l doing here?
我這是在幹嘛呀？
Yo, am l getting arrested for something?
我被逮捕了嗎？
No, you're not getting arrested. Come on. Come on.
沒有，進來
Whoa.
哇
-Okay. What are they saying? -l have no idea what they're saying.
-他們在說什麼？ -我不知道
You got no idea? l thought you said you spoke Albanian.
你說你會講阿爾巴尼亞話
No. l never said l speak Albanian.
我才沒這麼說
You said you spoke Albanian.
你有
l never said l speak Albanian.
我沒有
Well, how do you know it's Albanian?
你怎知是阿爾巴尼亞話？
My ex-wife and her parents are Albanian.
我前妻是阿爾巴尼亞人
Her parents couldn't speak English for shit.
她爸媽不會說英文
l have no idea what they're saying,
我完全聽不懂
but l'll tell you right now that the language is 100% Albanian.
不過百分百是阿爾巴尼亞話
-100%? -100%.
-百分百？ -百分百
Call the Albanian Consulate. See if they can get somebody over here
打給阿爾巴尼亞領事館
to translate this for us. Make it happen fast.
找一個翻譯來，快點
Okay, you hang out in the back for me, okay?
你留在後面
Oh, man, not again.
不是吧
Van was stolen two days ago, but it's clean. No prints.
箱型車是賊車，沒採到指紋
-Nothing? -Nothing.
-什麼線索也沒有？ -沒有
Albanian?
阿爾巴尼亞語？
My man, like l told you, 100% Albanian.
我說過，百分百阿爾巴尼亞語
Undeniable.
毫無疑問
-Hey. -Thanks.
-嘿 -謝謝
MAN: (ON VlDEO GAME) Yo, yo, yo. There go that motherfucker right there.
喂，那混帳東西在那裡
Hey, yo, you thought you was gonna get away with that shit, didn't you?
你以為你跑得掉嗎？
DALTON: How does this game work?
這遊戲怎麼玩？
You get points for doing dirt, like jacking a car or selling crack.
幹壞事就能得分 像是偷車或是販毒
And you lose points if someone jacks your ride or shoots you.
你被劫車或被幹掉就會失分
Come on, baby.
來呀
Take that! Take this! What? What? What?
去死吧
Talk shit now! I don't hear you!
你敢嗆聲，我聽不到
You're gone, baby! You're dead! Bye-bye!
你死定了，拜了！
DALTON: Jesus!
天啊
What's the point of this?
這有什麼意義？
Like my man 50 says, ''Get rich or die tryin'.''
我的偶像五角說過：「要錢不要命」
Yo, you'd get mad points for knocking over the bank.
搶銀行得分才多咧
-You think that's cool? -Hell, yeah. You trying to get paid, too.
-你覺得很棒嗎？ -對啊，你也想賺錢嘛
Finish your slice. l'll take you back to your father.
吃完了我就帶你找爸爸
l got to talk to him about this game.
我得叫他不准你玩這遊戲
-ls it good? -No doubt.
-好吃嗎？ -好吃
lt's gonna be okay.
不會有事的
Cool.
酷
You'll be home soon.
你很快就能回家
That's whassup.
棒呆了
-Sir? -Yeah.
-先生 -什麼事？
-No luck with the Albanian Consulate. -What do you mean?
-阿爾巴尼亞領事館不管用 -什麼意思？
l couldn't tell what the guy was talking about. l think he wanted money.
我聽不懂，對方好像要錢
And l tried the State Department. That takes a month.
找國務院要等一個月
Okay.
好吧
-Call her. -Are you crazy?
-打給她 -你瘋啦？
-l hate that bitch. Come on. -You said she speaks Albanian, right?
-我恨那婊子 -她會講阿爾巴尼亞語？
-Yeah, she was born there. -Call her.
-她在那兒出生 -打給她
l'm gonna regret this.
我一定會後悔
-Who's Detective Frazier? -Right here.
-哪位是費警探？ -我就是
-l have llina Maria over here. -Miritia.
-這是伊蘭娜瑪莉亞 -瑪莉亞塔
-Oh, how you doing? -Hello.
-你好 -哈羅
How you doing?
你好
-What's this? -Parking tickets. You can fix them?
-這是什麼？ -違規停車罰單，幫我註銷
Yeah, l'll see what l can do.
我盡量想辦法
Can you listen to this and tell us what they're saying?
請你告訴我們他們在說什麼
You can't smoke in here.
這裡不准吸煙
Shit. Go ahead.
儘管抽吧
What's so funny? What, you know what they're talking about?
有什麼好笑？他們在說什麼？
l know what they're talking about. l even know who it is.
我知道，我也知道是誰
You know who it is? You mean you know their names?
你知道他們的名字？
-Who? l mean, who is it? -Parking tickets?
-是誰？ -停車罰單呢？
-They're taken care of. Who is it? -lt's Enver Hoxha.
-搞定了 -那是哈恩維赫克薩
-Who? -He was the president of Albania.
-誰？ -阿爾巴尼亞前總統
Wait.
等等
You're telling me the former president of Albania is in there robbing a bank?
阿爾巴尼亞前總統是搶匪？
Enver Hoxha's dead.
他早就掛了
That's a tape of him discussing how Albanian people are great people.
這是錄音啦，他在大發厥詞 說阿爾巴尼亞人很偉大
They are immortal people. l wouldn't worry.
都是不死之身，我不會為這個擔心的
lt's a tape. You're sure about that?
你確定這是錄音？
l had to listen to all this nonsense in school.
我在學校每天都得聽
''Communism is great. Capitalism is evil. Lenin, Marx, blah, blah, blah.''
「共產主義最好，資本主義最壞 還有列寧、馬克斯什麼的」
lt's Enver Hoxha. lt's a tape.
這是哈恩維赫克薩的錄音
Okay. Okay, well, Officer, you can take her home.
帶她回家吧
And do me a favor, huh? Watch where you park next time, okay?
下次不要亂停車
So, they're playing tapes for us now.
他們放錄音帶？
They knew we were gonna bug them.
他們知道我們在竊聽
Yeah, you're damn right they knew we were gonna bug them. And they knew how.
一點也沒錯 他們也知道我們如何竊聽
What makes it even worse, they wanted us to bug them
更糟的是，他們要我們竊聽
so they could send us on a wild goose chase.
他們故意害我們浪費時間
Last time l had my johnson pulled that good, it cost me $5.
上次我像這樣被搞花了五塊錢
$5?
五塊錢？
Yeah, Tijuana. Don't ask.
墨西哥，別問了
Look at the... Oh, fuck that.
你看，去它的
-Detective Frazier. Nice to meet you. -My pleasure.
-費警探，幸會 -幸會
This is Madeleine White.
這位是麥德琳魏特
-How do you do, Miss White? -lt's an honor, Detective.
-你好，魏小姐 -幸會，警探
Miss White may be able to assist you.
魏小姐也許能協助你
Good. Good. What do you have in mind?
太好了，你有什麼想法？
She has a certain amount of influence in these matters
她有很大的影響力
for reasons which l can't share with you.
我不能跟你多說
What are you trying to say, sir?
這是什麼意思？
What the Mayor means is that there are matters at stake here
他的意思是你的官階不夠高
that are a little bit above your pay grade. No offense.
我不是故意冒犯
And he's offering to help you.
他也想幫助你
Well, why don't you just tell the Mayor to raise my pay grade to the proper level
那就請市長升我的官
and problem solved.
問題就解決了
From what l hear, that would have happened a long time ago
如果你圓滑一點
if you'd been a little bit more diplomatic. But we can certainly discuss it.
早就陞官了 這件事可以商量
Look, l'm kidding. l mean, l make First Grade when l make First Grade.
我在開玩笑啦 我要靠自己的能力陞官
You want to speed that up, l'm not gonna talk you out of it.
你想幫我一把也行
Then there's also the matter of $1 40,000 that seems to have walked away
你負責偵辦的販毒案
from the Madrugada check-cashing bust.
有一張14萬支票不翼而飛
Oh, l see.
我瞭了
Well, l had nothing to do with that.
那件事與我無關
HERNANDEZ: Yeah, Collins, we got snipers in the windows here.
狙擊手在隔壁大樓的屋頂…
We got guys in the building next door. Guys up on the roof.
以及窗口等待指令
We're trying to get the blueprints for the bank
我們也拿到銀行平面圖
so we can figure out the ventilator shaft. Maybe we can come down.
可以從通風孔進入銀行
DALTON: Well? FRAZlER: ls this the President of Albania?
-喂？ -阿爾巴尼亞總統嗎？
-Speaking. -Pretty funny.
-我就是 -很好笑
-You shouldn't eavesdrop on people. -Well, you better get used to it, pal.
-你不該偷聽別人講話 -你最好習慣
There's not gonna be much privacy where you're going.
監獄沒有隱私
You're damn right.
你說的對
This time next week, l'll be sucking down pina coladas
下禮拜我會一邊吸飲料
in a hot tub with six girls named Amber and Tiffany.
一邊和六個辣妹洗三溫暖
More like taking a shower with two guys named Jamal and Jesus,
你會和兩個彪形大漢洗戰鬥澡
if you know what l mean. And here's the bad news,
而且更慘的是
that thing you're sucking on, it's not a pina colada.
你吸的絕對是別的東西
-Maybe you like that kind of thing, huh? -You really want to piss me off.
-也許你就喜歡那調調 -你真的很想惹毛我
All right, here's where we stand.
情況是這樣
l don't need your fucking status report, Serpico.
你不必向我報告情況
l tell you where things stand.
讓我告訴你吧
-Sure, sure. l just meant... -Here's where things stand.
-好 -情況是這樣
You're getting me what l asked you for.
在時限內
You'll have it ready in the time l gave you
把我要的東西給我
or you'll sit by and you'll watch me do just what l said l would do. Clear?
不然就等著看我大開殺戒，瞭嗎？
Very clear. l'm trying to get you what you want.
我瞭，我正在努力
But you got to understand this.
不過你也要知道
You know, it's not like the City of New York has 7 47 s waiting around for days like today.
747噴射客機不是說有就有
l understand that if you don't get my plane ready,
我知道，你弄不到一架飛機
-then you might as well send a hearse. -Please.
-就送一具棺材進來吧 -別這樣
Let's focus on how we can both get what we want, all right?
讓我們好好商量該怎麼合作
Hey! You're not listening.
你沒在聽
You get me what l want, l won't kill anyone.
我拿到我要的就不會殺人
All right. l'm on it. l'm on it.
好，我這就去辦
Let's just try to keep everybody calm, okay?
試著冷靜下來
-Don't l sound calm to you? -Yeah, you do.
-我聽起來不夠冷靜嗎？ -你聽起來非常冷靜
FRAZlER: Yeah, you do.
你太冷靜了
-So, Mr. Damerjian... -Damerjian.
-德瑪吉先生 -德莫吉
-Damerjian. ls that Albanian? -Just call me Kenneth.
-那是阿爾巴尼亞名字嗎？ -叫我肯尼
-Kenneth? -ls that Albanian or...
-肯尼？ -你是阿爾巴尼亞人嗎？
lt's Armenian.
亞美尼亞人
What's the difference?
有什麼不同？
Detective, l was born in Queens.
我在皇后區出生
l've never been to Armenia, Albania. l went surfing in Australia once.
沒去過亞美尼亞或阿爾巴尼亞 只去過奧洲一次
Can l have a glass of water?
我能喝水嗎？
-Are you thirsty? -My throat's parched.
-你口渴？ -我的喉嚨很干
-l'm not nervous. -Your throat's parched?
-我不是緊張 -你的喉嚨很干？
-My throat's parched. -His throat is parched.
-很干 -他的喉嚨很干
-l just want a glass of water. -Oh, shit!
-我只想喝水 -你真逗
When you start telling us what really happened...
先說出事情經過
-l just want a glass of water. -His throat is parched.
-我只想喝水 -他的喉嚨很干
-Here. You want some coffee? -No, that's all right.
-你要喝咖啡嗎？ -不要
-l don't drink that stuff. -No, go ahead.
-我不喝咖啡 -喝吧
Did you know they were robbing the bank?
你知道這是搶案嗎？
l didn't know they were robbing the bank until they pulled a gun in my face.
他們掏出槍來才知道
ls that why you held the door open for them?
所以你才幫他們開門？
How do you know they robbed the bank?
你怎麼知道他們是搶匪？
Because they pulled a gun in my face...
他們拿槍指著我
That doesn't mean they were robbing the bank.
那並不代表他們是搶匪
Did they take money? Did you see them take money?
你有看到他們搶錢嗎？
l was in a bank and l was locked up for who knows how long.
我被關在銀行不知道多久
-Okay. -Tied up in a room. l saw you see me.
-好 -雙手被反綁，你明明看到我
You saw me see you?
你看到我看到你？
-ls that what you just said? -Yeah.
-你是這個意思嗎？ -對
l was locked up in the room. You saw me gagged when you came in.
我被關在房間裡 你進來的時候看到我被反綁
Listen, l can't work miracles over here. l'm gonna need more time.
我不是神，我需要時間
Well, perhaps if you'd use the time that l gave you more efficiently,
你應該善用我給你的時間
you wouldn't be having this problem.
就不會有這個問題
-What do you want me to say? -That my plane is ready.
-你要我說什麼？ -我的飛機準備好了
Okay, listen.
聽好
l promise you, as God is my witness, l'm working on it as hard as l can.
我對天發誓，我正在盡力
lt's just gonna take a few more hours.
再給我幾小時
Why should l give you any more time?
我幹嘛再多給你時間？
Well, it's simple. You give me more time, you get what you want.
你給我時間就會得到你要的
You don't give me the time, you don't get what you want.
不然你什麼都得不到
You got nothing to lose.
反正你沒任何損失
Meanwhile, we'll send in some more food.
我們會送更多食物進去
l got a question for you. You get it right, l give you more time.
我有個謎題 答對了就給你多一點時間
-And? -You know what happens if you don't.
-答錯呢？ -你知道後果是什麼
Which weighs more?
哪一個比較重？
All the trains that pass through Grand Central Station in a year,
一年經過中央站的火車
or the trees cut down to print all US currency in circulation?
或是用來印美鈔砍的樹比較重？
Here's a hint. lt's a trick question.
這是腦筋急轉彎問題
What the hell is that? Playing games now?
搞什麼？猜謎遊戲嗎？
lt's the trains.
火車比較重
US money isn't printed on paper at all. lt's cotton.
美鈔是用棉布不是用紙印的
-Yeah, l heard that. -Yeah, that's right.
-我聽過 -沒錯
-Okay. -So no trees were cut down.
-好 -根本就不必砍樹
-Are you sure? -Yeah. 100%.
-你確定？ -百分百確定
Okay.
好吧
l got it.
我有答案了
-Wait a second. Wait a second. -l'll call you back.
-等一下 -我再打給你
lt's a trap. They both weigh the same.
這是圈套，兩者一樣重
Tell him they both weigh the same. They both weigh nothing.
兩者一樣重，都沒有重量
They both weigh nothing or they both weigh the same?
是沒重量還是一樣重？
Tell him they both weigh the same.
兩者一樣重
Do it now.
跟他說一樣重，就這麼說
They both weigh the same. Got it.
都一樣重，知道了
-Well? -They both weigh the same.
-怎樣？ -它們都一樣重
This time, send sandwiches.
這次我要三明治
That's pretty good. This guy's nuts.
不錯，這傢伙瘋了
He said, ''Grand Central Station.''
他說「中央站」
Grand Central Terminal is the train station.
中央車站才是火車站
-Grand Central Station is the post office. -ls the post office.
-中央站是郵局 -郵局
DARlUS: He's wrong. FRAZlER: Who's wrong?
-他錯了 -誰？
Perp One. Trains don't pass through Grand Central.
搶匪呀 火車不會經過中央車站
lt's the last stop for every train.
那是火車的終點站
-What about the subway? They run through. -Metro-North goes there.
-地鐵列車呢？ -北線地鐵會經過中央車站
-How the fuck do you know? -Metro-North goes there!
-你知道什麼？ -北線地鐵會經過那兒
No. Metro-North starts there.
那是北線地鐵的起點啦
What are you guys talking about? Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
你們到底在說什麼？
-Metro-North goes through! -Let's just get the sandwiches.
-北線地鐵會經過那兒 -去買三明治吧
-Metro-North... -Deal is, he said, ''Passes through.''
-北線地鐵… -可是他說經過耶
Yeah, but the Metro-North goes up there, though.
北線地鐵會經過那兒呀
Look, shut up. lt doesn't matter, anyway.
別吵了，這不重要
ROURKE: (OVER TRANSMlTTER) I know what he meant.
他說的話跟他的意思不同
DARlUS: Yeah. That's always a problem, isn't it?
-這是個問題 -三明治
ROURKE: I'm on it, I'm on it.
我這就去
CHAlM: You know, right now l could go for a nice kosher hot dog and a beer.
我好想吃猶太熱狗喝啤酒
SETH: l had Met tickets tonight. And Pedro's pitching!
我本來要去看大都會職棒賽
GLADYS: They're gonna get their asses kicked anyway.
反正他們會輸得很慘
SETH: Tell me about it. l'm better off here. BRAD: l'm glad they didn't separate us.
-沒錯 -幸好我們沒被拆散
-Do you think they're terrorists? -They're robbers, not terrorists.
-他們是恐怖份子嗎？ -他們是搶匪啦
How do you know? They could be Al-Qaeda.
你怎麼知道？搞不好是基地組織
Trust me. l've studied these things.
相信我，我很有研究
-What are you, Mossad? -No. l was a lawyer.
-你是以色列情報局幹員嗎？ -我以前是律師
Now l teach courses at Columbia Law on genocide, slave labor,
現在是哥倫比亞大學法學院教授 教種族屠殺、奴工
-war reparation claims. -Mira.
-和戰爭賠償 -那…
-Can l sue anybody when this is over? -Oh, sure. Go nuts.
-結束後我能告任何人嗎？ -當然羅
Go meshuga.
申請國賠吧
Now that's a good looking shithole.
這會是個不錯的屎坑
-Hello? -FRAZlER: Hey, baby, how you doing?
-喂？ -寶貝，你好嗎？
Baby, I'm worried about you. You coming home?
我好擔心，你要回家嗎？
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Soon.
就快了
lt's gonna be a long night, though, so don't wait up for me.
今晚不行，不用等我
Why don't you let me come down there?
我不能去嗎？
Because l don't want to be distracted by you, that's why.
我不想被你分心
Well, if you're still there when I come on duty in the morning, you will see me.
如果我去執勤你就會看到我
-l cannot wait. l cannot wait. -So, how you doing?
-我等不及了 -還好吧？
lt's all right. We got a couple of the hostages out. Thanks a lot.
還好，兩名人質被放出來
-No, no. How you doing? -l'm doing okay. l'm doing all right.
-我說的是你 -我很好
Oh, I saw the Mayor on TV. He said you're doing a great job. I saw you, too.
市長在電視上說你表現得很好 我也看到你了
-You saw me on TV? -Yeah.
-真的假的？ -真的
-How'd l look? -You looked good, baby. Real good.
-我帥不帥？ -超帥的
-All right, listen. l got to go. -All right. Hey.
-我得走了 -好
-Keep your head down. -All right, l will. Love you.
-小心點 -我會的，我愛你
Come on.
來吧
So, are we clear about the ground rules?
你知道基本規則吧？
-There's no need to worry, Detective. -l get paid to worry, okay?
-別擔心 -當警察一定會擔心
l just need you to look me in the eye
我要你看著我
and make me believe that you understand everything we talked about.
告訴我你瞭解我們同意的事
-l understand. -Okay.
-我瞭解 -好
Someone here wants to talk to you.
有人想跟你講話
-Hello? -Who is this?
-喂？ -你是哪位？
Let's not get into any names.
我的名字不重要
-What matters is what l can offer you. -And what's that?
-我能給你什麼才重要 -你能給我什麼？
Well, if l can be assured that certain interests are protected,
如果你能保護某些利益
l might be able to help you get what you came for.
我就能幫你拿到你想要的
l doubt that.
不太可能
Tell me about these interests that you are trying to protect.
你想保護的利益是什麼？
Why don't you let me worry about that?
讓我來擔心這件事
Now, what is it you were hoping to get out of all this?
你到底想要什麼？
-Rich, of course. -Of course.
-發大財 -當然
But you may have bitten off more than you can chew.
也許你沒有發橫財的命
-How? -l can't discuss that on the phone.
-怎麼說？ -我不方便在電話上談
-You work for the bank? -No.
-你替銀行做事？ -不是
And you're not a cop.
你也不是警察？
That's right.
沒錯
Come on in.
進來吧
You got 10 minutes. No more.
你只有十分鐘
lf you're not out before the lights come back on,
時間到了不出來
you can stay inside until this thing is over.
就待在裡頭吧
-You don't need to threaten me. -That's not a threat, lady, but this is.
-你不必威脅我 -並沒有
l know this game is a mile over my head, but l'm telling you, if you fuck me over...
這整件事已經超出我的理解範圍 如果你敢整我…
l got where l am by collecting friends, not enemies.
我只會交朋友，不會樹敵
Trust me, okay?
相信我
You're on your own.
自求多福吧
DALTON: What makes you think l need help?
你憑什麼認為我需要幫助？
MADELElNE: Well, the hundred people outside, for starters.
外頭有一百個警察
DALTON: lt's not a problem.
這不是問題
MADELElNE: And they're fueling your jet right now as we speak.
他們才不會替你弄到飛機
Come on. You're not that stupid.
你不會這麼傻吧
Here's what l'm thinking.
我的想法是
lf you give up now, l can ensure that you'll serve the minimum.
現在投降，我保證…
l'm thinking three years, four years at the most.
你只要坐三、四年牢
You can arrange that?
你這麼有辦法？
Well, you haven't hurt anyone or stolen anything,
你沒傷害人質或搶走錢
so yes, as a matter of fact, l can.
當然沒問題
-lt's not good enough. -Well, l wasn't finished.
-這還不夠 -我還沒說完
When you get out, you'll have $2 million.
等你出獄就會有兩百萬元
Will l? How?
是嗎？怎麼會？
We'll put it someplace safe and it'll be waiting for you when you get out.
你一出獄就會拿到錢
Thanks.
謝了
But no, thanks.
不過敬謝不敏
Oh, come on. l made you such a sweet offer.
這是很好的條件
l really don't think you have much in the way of alternatives.
你並沒有其它選擇
Why don't you talk to me about these interests that you're in here to protect?
跟我談談你要保護的利益
-l'm afraid l can't. -l can.
-我不能談 -我可以
Let me tell you a story.
讓我說個故事給你聽
During World War ll, there was an American working for a bank in Switzerland.
二次大戰期間 有一個美國人替瑞士銀行做事
DALTON: Now, I don't need to tell you that this period in history
我不說你也知道在這段時期
was rife with opportunity for people of low morals.
這種沒道德良知的投機份子很多
People like this man.
就跟這個人一樣
people were being stripped of everything they owned.
眼睜睜看著無辜百姓被剝奪一切
Then he used his blood money to start a bank.
他用這筆黑心錢成立銀行
Now,
你…
does this sound like it might be the man you work for?
是不是剛好替這個人做事？
Or am l just whistling Dixie out of my ass?
還是我講的都是屁話？
-l believe we understand each other. -Good.
-咱們心照不宣 -很好
So, what the hell can you do for me
你到底能為我做什麼？
since l clearly know more than you do, and l've planned this to perfection?
我知道的比你多，計劃完全無缺
Believe me, if l need to, l can change your entire program.
相信我，我可以改變你的計劃
So, the sooner that you stop being my problem
只要你不要成為我的問題
and you start becoming my solution, the better off you'll be.
而是我的解答，你就比較好過
-What is it you want? -Two minutes.
-你要什麼？ -兩分鐘
The safety deposit box room. l just need to go to one box.
我只要到保險庫 拿一個保險箱的東西
Looking for this?
你在找這玩意嗎？
This could be very embarrassing to your employer.
這對你的老闆非常不利
He should have destroyed this a long time ago.
他早該把它毀了
He didn't, so now it's mine.
但是卻沒有，現在是我的
Now, if the day ever comes where l have to stand before a judge
如果有一天我被逮捕
and account for what l did here,
接受審判
you and your boss will do whatever it takes to help me.
你和你老闆要盡全力幫助我
You get out of here with that envelope,
你帶著信封走出去
and we'll pay you a lot of money.
我們就會給你一大筆錢
l'll keep that in mind.
我會記得這一點
You're not gonna tell me how you're planning to get out of here, are you?
你到底打算怎麼出去？
l'm gonna walk right out the front door. Anything else?
直接走出大門，還有問題嗎？
-How did you know about all this? -Doesn't matter.
-你怎麼知道這件事？ -這不重要
Fact is, all lies, all evil deeds, they stink.
所有的謊言和惡行都會被揭穿
You can cover them up for a while, but they don't go away.
只能遮掩一時，不能永遠逃避
-Murder will out? -Precisely.
-罪有應得？ -沒錯
Well, l still don't get what you're doing here.
我還是不知道你的目的
Really?
是嗎？
DALTON: Good.
很好
So, we spoke.
我們談過話
Oh, no. You're gonna have to give me more than that.
我要知道更多
-Let me have this window, fellows. -Yes, sir.
-讓一下 -是的
l told him that, well, since he hadn't killed anyone,
我跟他說既然他還沒殺人
it wasn't too late to surrender and get off with a lighter sentence.
只要投降就能從輕發落
And?
然後呢？
And that was basically it.
差不多就這樣
You know, l don't ordinarily get offended
別人把我當白癡
the first time somebody treats me like an idiot, but you are pushing it.
我通常不會生氣，不過你太超過了
Now, l know you did not go in there to tell this guy something he already knew.
你並不是跟他說他知道的事實
Talk to me.
老實跟我說
Look, Detective.
聽好
Our arrangement doesn't include me giving you a detailed explanation.
我並沒有答應告訴你一切
l say it does, okay?
你要老實說
Okay, you don't own me.
我可沒被你收買
This check-cashing thing, this coke bust, l can face that on my own.
我自己可以面對風紀組調查
l know what l did and what l didn't do.
我很清楚我沒有做錯事
-Talk to me. -Off the record?
-快說吧 -你能夠保密？
''Off the...'' Everything about you is off the record. Just talk to me.
和你有關的都很神秘，說吧
-Well, l gave him an incentive. -Okay.
-我開了一個條件給他 -好
-Did he go for it? -No. But l'd say he's considering it.
-他有沒有接受？ -沒有，他說他會考慮
He's smart, isn't he?
他很聰明，對吧？
-He thinks he is. -Yeah.
-他自以為他很聰明 -對
One of your types, like the lvy League type?
他跟你一樣是名校出身？
-Clearly well educated. -That's what l'm talking about.
-他的確受過良好教育 -我就是這個意思
That's exactly what l'm talking about.
我就是這個意思
You talk like him, so think like him. What do you think he's gonna do?
你的談吐和思想都跟他很像 你認為他會怎麼做？
-Well, he's not gonna kill anyone. -How do you know?
-他不會殺人 -為什麼？
-Because he's not a murderer.
-他不是殺人犯 -你怎麼知道？
l got news for you. Most of the guys up in Sing Sing
殺人犯通常不知道
weren't murderers until they killed somebody.
自己會殺人
You never know what a person will do until you push him into a corner.
人被逼到困境什麼事都做得出來
But it doesn't seem like you've pushed him into a corner.
你並沒有把他逼到困境
lt doesn't, does it? Seems more like he chose the corner.
沒錯，是他把自己逼到困境
You're right.
你說的對
So, you through?
你的事辦完了嗎？
-l guess. Are you saying l'm dismissed? -Yes, l am.
-對，你要趕我走了？ -沒錯
You got a card, in case l need to call you?
你有名片嗎？我可能需要打給你
Please don't take this personally, but no.
不要生氣
l don't think you can afford me.
你付不起我的費用
Well, don't take this personally, Miss White. Kiss my black ass, okay?
你也別生氣，去你的
Careful, Detective Frazier. My bite's much worse than my bark.
說話小心點，我可不是好惹的
-So, how old are you, Brian? -Eight and three-quarters.
-布萊恩，你幾歲？ -八又四分之三
Eight and three-quarters. Big boy.
八又四分之三，很大羅
-Were you scared in there? -No.
-你害怕嗎？ -不怕
-No? Not at all, huh? -Nope. l'm from Brooklyn.
-一點都不怕？ -對，我來自布魯克林
You're from Brooklyn, huh? l understand.
布魯克林？
-Guns don't scare me. -They don't scare you?
-我什麼都不怕 -是嗎？
-Brave, too, huh? -Yeah.
-你很勇敢羅？ -對
So the guys that had the guns, do you remember them saying anything?
拿槍的人有沒有說什麼？
-Yeah. -What'd they say?
-有 -他說什麼？
They asked me about my game.
他問我在玩什麼遊戲
-Who did? -The guy that robbed the bank. Duh.
-誰？ -那個搶匪呀，豬頭
Son, be respectful.
兒子，別罵人
Okay, Brooklyn. But it... Was he the one in charge?
好吧，他是頭頭嗎？
-Uh-huh. -Okay.
好
And you don't remember anything else?
你不記得別的事？
He was kind of tall.
他很高
He had a mask.
戴了面罩
Brian, you think you can recognize him in any of these pictures?
布萊恩，你認得出他嗎？
Take your time. Have a good look.
慢慢來，仔細看
Let's keep that over there. Just take a look.
仔細看這些照片
-With the mask, they look all the same. -lt's true.
-他們戴了面罩看起來都一樣 -沒錯
With the mask, they all look the same. That's right, Brian.
戴了面罩看起來都一樣
Attempted robbery. Liquor store.
搶劫雜貨店未遂
Well, this was a real step up for a small-timer like you, huh?
搶銀行算是很大的進步羅
l got to hand it to you, Pablo.
你真有一套，帕羅
First of all, it's Paul. Not Pablo, okay?
我叫保羅，不是帕羅
Excuse me.
對不起
-You want some gum? -No.
-吃口香糖嗎？ -不要
And second, l didn't do it, all right?
而且不是我幹的
What? l made a few mistakes when l was a kid.
我年輕的時候誤入歧途
l was out with some friends and they held up a liquor store.
我的朋友搶劫我剛好也在
What was l supposed to do?
我該怎麼辦？
Where'd you grow up, you Wassa Wassa, Park Avenue?
你是不知民間疾苦的花花大少？
-What's that? Wassa what? What'd you say? -Wassa Wassa.
-花什麼？ -花花大少
You know, a person that don't come to your neighborhood.
我看你也不像
How do you say ''Rikers lsland'' in Spanish?
監獄西班牙話怎麼說？
What about these two?
這兩個呢？
That ring a bell?
有印象嗎？
These two? No.
這兩個？沒有
-Nothing? -Nothing.
-完全沒有？ -沒有
Don't they look suspicious to you?
你不覺得他們可疑嗎？
l mean, l would think that you would want to know who they are.
你不想知道他們是誰？
No.
不想
-Well, thank you very much. -Thank you.
-謝謝你的合作 -謝謝
Hey, just out of curiosity do you know anything about diamonds?
你對鑽石知道多少？
A bit. What do you need?
不少，你需要什麼？
What do you think a guy like me should pay for a diamond ring?
一隻鑽戒要多少錢？
Depends. How many carats?
這要看是幾克拉
lf you'd like, l could give you my nephew's number.
找我侄子
-Okay. -You'll get a very good deal.
-好 -他會給你打折
What do you have on underneath?
底下是什麼？
-Excuse me? -Underneath your painter's coat?
-什麼？ -你的衣服底下穿什麼？
-What do you have on underneath? -Clothing.
-你底下穿什麼？ -小可愛
Could you show us, please?
讓我們看
You see, there's just you and one other woman
你和另一個女人
that fit the physical description of the female suspect.
符合女嫌犯特徵
What's that?
什麼特徵？
lt's your height, your age, and your...
身高、年齡還有…
Your cup size.
罩杯大小
So, l violated Section 34 double-D?
我違反了第34條DD條款嗎？
That's what you're telling me?
是不是這意思？
How dumb do these morons have to be to think they're gonna get a plane?
這白癡真以為會有飛機嗎？
This guy's no moron.
他不是白癡
l don't just mean him. Any hostage taker.
不只是他，每一個挾持人質者
Those ragheads at the Munich Olympics.
慕尼黑奧運那些恐怖份子
Who the fuck ever got a plane?
他們上得了飛機嗎？
Shit, and these days? This guy doesn't know that?
難道他不知道嗎？
REPORTER: (ON TV) The area is flooded
這裡戒備深嚴，狙擊手在屋頂…
What you doing there, Keith?
你在幹嘛？
He wants a plane. l'm gonna give him a plane.
他要飛機我就給他飛機
-What happened to playing it by the book? -That's what's bugging me.
-你不遵守談判手冊？ -我就是覺得不對勁
lt's like the other team read the book, too, and they know exactly what we're gonna do.
他們好像也看過談判手冊
This whole time, we're trying to stall him, right?
從頭到尾都不是我們在拖延時間
Wrong. They're the ones that are stalling.
而是他們在拖延時間
Think about it. The bullshit questions, the Albanian thing...
什麼狗屁謎語、阿爾巴尼亞錄音
So, you're saying he what?
這代表什麼？
l'm saying that he wants to give us more time. He makes demands.
他要給我們更多時間 他提出要求和時限
He gives us deadlines. We stall. Then he gives us more time.
我們盡量拖，他就給更多時間
l don't think he's in a rush.
他一點都不急
-Why? -That's what l'm gonna find out.
-為什麼？ -我要去查清楚
-Yeah. -Your plane is ready.
-喂？ -飛機準備好了
ls that a fact?
是嗎？
That's a fact, but I'm gonna need something from you first.
對，不過你要先為我做一件事
l'm gonna need to come in there and make sure the hostages are okay.
我要親眼看到人質平安無事
You'll see them when they get on the bus.
你會在巴士上看到他們
l just need to make sure you're not leaving any bodies behind.
我要確定你沒留下任何人
Meet me at the front door.
到前門找我
-What the hell just happened? -You got to be crazy to go in there.
-怎麼回事？ -你瘋了才會進去
DALTON: Down the stairs.
樓下
-Gum? -Excuse me?
-口香糖？ -什麼？
-Would you like some gum? -No, thank you.
-你要吃口香糖嗎？ -不要，謝了
Let me take the kid.
讓我把小孩帶走
No.
不行
Any more?
還有嗎？
There are some who misbehaved.
有些人不乖乖聽話
Please help me!
救我！
Please help us!
救我們！
Please help us! Please!
請你救救我們！
We're gonna get you all out of here.
我們一定會救你們出去
l promise you.
我保證
Tour is over.
參觀結束
-Can l ask you a question? -There is nothing to talk about.
-我問你一個問題 -沒什麼好談的
What were you planning on doing
我真的弄到飛機
if you actually got the plane and the pilots, huh?
你會怎樣？
-Excuse me? -You don't want a plane. You never did.
-什麼？ -你從頭到尾都不要飛機
Who ever heard of bank robbers escaping on a plane with 50 hostages?
誰聽過銀行搶匪帶人質逃逸？
You saw Dog Day Afternoon. You're stalling. Why? l don't know.
你也看過《熱天午後》 你一直在拖延時間
What's the matter? You can't get into the safe?
我不知道為什麼 怎麼？打不開保險庫？
Perhaps.
也許吧
There's two ways out of this.
你只有兩個選擇
The easy way, we walk out the front door together, or the hard boys cut the power,
跟我一起走出這道門 或是讓霹靂小組進行攻堅
hit you with the tear gas, and come in strong through the glass.
丟催淚彈，闖進來火拚一場
lt's your choice. You don't want that. l don't want that.
你我都不希望有這種結果
And, you know, they'd like to do it tonight.
他們今晚就想行動
You got night vision?
你們有夜視鏡
-You got gas masks? -Maybe.
-和防毒面罩嗎？ -也許有
-l'm this close to ordering it. -Let's cut the crap.
-我就快要下令攻堅了 -廢話少說
First, you don't order an assault when no hostages have been killed
沒有死傷或威脅
and there's no immediate threat.
不能下令攻堅
Second, if it ends that way, whatever happens,
如果真的要火拚一場
you don't get to be the hero.
你的麻煩就大了
You want to bullshit me, try harder.
你想唬我，想都別想
Let's go.
走吧
Okay.
好
l tell you what. My ass is covered, sport.
告訴你，我不會有麻煩
But l would not get too comfortable in here if l were you.
你也別想在這兒舒服地享福
No? l got the cable guy coming on Wednesday.
才怪，禮拜三要裝第四台了
-Why don't you just walk out the door? -l will.
-你何不走出大門？ -我會的
l'm gonna walk out of that door when l'm good and ready.
我準備好就會大搖大擺走出去
Can l get you to do that today?
今天行不行？
l didn't think so.
不行
Any other proposals?
你有其它要求嗎？
Oh, please. Do not say ''proposals.''
別說「求」這個字
My girlfriend, she wants a proposal from me.
我女友要我跟她求婚
-You think you're too young to get married? -No, l'm not too young. Too broke.
-你覺得太年輕不想安定下來？ -不是太年輕，是太窮了
Maybe l should rob a bank.
也許我也該搶銀行
You love each other?
你們真心相愛嗎？
Yeah. Yeah, we do.
當然了
Then money shouldn't really matter.
那錢就不是問題
Thank you, bank robber.
多謝開導，銀行搶匪
l'm just saying money can't buy love.
我只是說金錢買不到真愛
Thank you very much. l'm...
我真心地謝謝你
l'm learning so much today, you know?
我今天學到好多
Look, why don't we go across the street to the Killarney Rose, huh?
咱們不如一起去對街的酒吧
Forget about this dangerous hostage situation.
忘了這件事
-l'll buy you a beer. My treat. -Thanks, Detective,
-我請你喝酒 -謝了，警探
but l'm trying to stay away from bars, if you know what l mean.
我還不想坐牢
Well, if you change your mind there's still a standing offer, all right?
你再好好考慮一下
Cellblock or the graveyard?
你想被關進監牢
Prison whites or a toe tag?
還是埋在墳墓？
-Make up your mind. Tick tock, tick tock. -Hey! Hey!
-最好趕快決定，分秒必爭 -嘿！
We done?
你鬧夠了嗎？
You just crossed the fucking line!
你做得太過份了
Buses, Kojak, parked outside.
巴士，停在外面
You think l'm bluffing?
你以為我在虛張聲勢？
You roll the dice and see what happens.
你就等著瞧吧
COP: All right. Now get the bunker up.
舉起盾牌
-So, what's up? -Got him right where l want him.
-怎麼樣？ -我讓他完全掌控大局
Yeah? Where's that?
怎麼說？
Right behind me with my pants around my ankles, but it's a start.
我讓他把我吃得死死的
Jesus Christ.
天啊
-What the fuck, man? -How long?
-搞什麼？ -還要多久？
-He got the drop on you! -Two.
-他把你撂倒了 -兩小時
-How long? -What if he saw your face?
-多久？ -他看到你的臉怎麼辦？
-Two. -What if l didn't have my gun?
-兩小時 -如果我當時沒槍怎麼辦？
Two, maybe three hours.
兩、三小時
You know, you're letting this cop get too fucking close.
你讓那警察太接近了
What happened?
怎麼回事？
l gave him every excuse to blow my brains out.
我給他很多藉口把我一槍轟掉
Yeah.
對
He doesn't bite. Why? He ain't the type.
他卻沒下手，為什麼？他不會殺人
Let's just step back and think about this for a second.
讓我們好好想想這一點
We know that they planned this whole thing. The tape, the cameras, the costumes.
他一切都計劃周詳 錄音帶、攝影機、工作服
There was a game plan, but it never included airplanes.
計劃並不包括飛機
He's up to something but it ain't violence.
他另有目的，但是不會傷人
FRAZlER: l'm listening. DALTON: How's the reception?
-我在聽 -收訊品質如何？
-Excuse me? -The camera on the truck.
-什麼？ -車上的攝影機
Give me a close-up on the second-floor window.
給二樓窗口來個特寫鏡頭
-Rourke? -l'm on it, l'm on it.
-小駱？ -馬上好
No, no, no, no, no, no! Fuck!
不要！
Oh, shit.
我靠
Keith! Keith! Keith!
基斯！
What are you doing? What the fuck are you doing?
你在幹什麼？
You mean beyond the obvious?
這不是很明顯嗎？
That's what l mean. Come on, this ain't no bank robbery!
你並不是在搶銀行
This is your fault. l told you to get the buses.
這是你的錯，我叫你準備巴士
Fuck you! l didn't kill anybody.
去你的，我沒有殺任何人
l got 50 more people in here. You fuck with me again,
我還有五十個人質，你敢再惹我
l'll give you two of the longest days of your life.
這兩天會很漫長
All right, look, just tell me what it is you really want and l'll get it for you.
告訴我你到底要什麼 我一定替你辦到
-l promise. -l've told you. Two buses, a plane.
-我保證 -我說過，兩輛巴士、一架飛機
Right, right. And box seats behind home plate at Yankee Stadium.
還有洋基球場的貴寶包廂票
Come on, don't bullshit a bullshitter.
別再唬弄我
You planned every inch of this thing right from the start.
你的計劃周詳
You got everybody marching to your beat, including me, and l'm through buying it.
我們都被你牽著鼻子走 不過我不隨你起舞了
You're too damn smart to be a cop.
你太聰明，不該當警察
Now get the fuck out of here.
給我滾出去
What? You going to shoot me?
你要殺我嗎？
Do it. Shit, you got nothing to lose.
下手呀，你都殺了人了
l damn sure ain't got nothing to lose, so shoot me.
沒什麼好損失的，開槍呀
Do it.
下手呀
-Shoot me. -Fuck you.
-殺了我 -去你的
Tell them to send someone sane over here.
叫他們派個正常人來
We got a big problem.
出了大問題
Hey, Detective, this ain't your day.
今天你衰斃了
How you doing, Captain?
你好，隊長
Look, l know you put your trust in me and l just...
我知道你信任我
Well, you're a good cop. Frazier, l need more like you.
你是個好警察
But if you're going down on this one, l can't go with you.
不過這次我不能被你拖下水
You got to understand this, though, sir...
你要明白…
No, no, no. Let me just tell you what my problem is, okay?
我的問題是
l go to bed, everything's hunky-dory.
我上床睡覺，一切OK
l get a call at 3:15, and there's what? A dead hostage.
到了半夜就死了一個人質
-Right, right, right. But l can end this... -lt is ended.
-對，不過我能阻止他… -事情結束了
See, you think l got options.
我也別無選擇
l got to answer to the Chief of D's.
這是上頭的命令
Darius is calling the shots on this. That's it.
戴隊長負責指揮攻堅行動
Hey, Sarge.
嘿，警官
-What'd he say? -That's it.
-他怎麼說？ -就這樣
Shit.
可惡
DARlUS: lt's a tactical nightmare. COUGHLlN: l know.
-這是一場惡夢 -我知道
Well, first, this is the only way in.
這是唯一的入口
Then we got to make it up the stairs blind.
然後要摸黑到樓上
Once we get up there, we're right out in the open.
一上去立刻成為標靶
DARlUS: They have the advantage of cover. They can pick us off like sitting ducks.
對方有掩護，可以一一把我們打掛
Then if we make it across the floor and down the stairs,
到了樓下也一樣
we still can't tell the homies from the good guys until they shoot at us.
也分不出誰是壞人誰是好人
Even if it isn't rigged with explosives, it's still a fucking nightmare.
就算沒有炸彈，也是惡夢一場
Move! Move! Move!
上，上
HOSTAGE: Open the door!
開門
COP 1 : Keep moving. COP 2: To the right.
-繼續前進 -往右
COP 3: Watch the hands, watch the hands.
注意情況
And let's not forget the possibility of hostages being killed.
人質一定會死傷慘重
Right now! Put the gun down!
把槍放下！
Back off or l shoot! l said back off!
退後！不然我就開槍
DARlUS: Well, our best hope is to separate them from the hostages.
唯一的機會是讓搶匪落單
lf we can get two or three upstairs and take them out?
在樓上把他們除掉
Kill them?
射死他們？
COP: Gun! Gun! Gun!
對方有槍！
What if there's more than four?
對方不只四個怎麼辦？
Yeah, well, that's what's so nuts about it. Anybody in a painter's suit could be a perp.
穿工作服的人都可能是嫌犯
Maybe we should dress our guys up like a bunch of painters.
也許我們也該穿工作服
And we should use rubber bullets. Take head shots. Put their lights out.
用橡膠子彈，瞄準頭部，把他們打昏
ED: Not a bad idea. COUGHLlN: Yeah.
-好主意 -對
COUGHLlN: Rubber bullets it is, baby.
那就用橡膠子彈吧
lf this goes down wrong,
這件事最後死傷慘重
they're going to dump this whole mess in your lap, you know?
責任都會推到你身上
-l'm making First Grade. -What?
-我要升任高級警探 -什麼？
l'm making Detective First Grade. Things ain't all they appear to be.
我要升任高級警探，眼見不能為憑
-What the fuck does that mean? -Detective First Grade Keith Frazier.
-什麼意思？ -高級警探費基斯
-Are you fucking kidding me? -Yes.
-你在開玩笑吧？ -對
Thank the Mayor and our mystery guest for that.
多謝市長和神秘貴寶
You cut a deal with those guys?
你和他們談條件？
Never make First Grade? Shit.
我一定會升任高級警探
Worked too hard to let that happen.
我太努力了
Everybody's getting theirs. l'm gonna get mine.
大家都陞官，我也要陞官
l'll be outside.
我會在外面
What a day, what a day.
太扯了，太扯了
Detective, they're gonna storm that bank without you? lt's not right.
攻堅行動你不參一腳？這不公平
So, tell me about the kid who pointed the gun at you, the 1 2-year-old.
談談12歲小子拿槍指住你
-Now? -Yeah.
-現在？ -對
Last year, up in the 33rd,
去年在33管區
l was breaking up a fight about a half a block from the high school.
我到一所高中附近勸阻一場打架
This one little spic is getting his clock cleaned by another one.
小西班牙佬被扁得倒在地上
Do me a favor, Sergeant. Just tone down the color commentary.
拜託，別用種族歧視字眼
So l bust up the fight,
我把他們拆散
l turn around and this kid is pointing a .22 at my chest.
一轉頭這小子就拿槍指住我
-ls that right? Now, which kid was this? -Another kid, an African-American.
-那小子是什麼人？ -一個非裔美國人
-An African-American, right? -Yeah.
-非裔美國人 -對
Came out of nowhere. l didn't see him.
他突然冒出來
So, what'd you do?
後來怎樣？
What did l do then? l'll tell you what l did then.
我告訴你
l got shot in the fucking chest. That's what l did then.
我胸口中了一槍
Yeah, so you'll pardon my euphemisms, Detective,
恕我直言哦，警探
but l would rather wind up an old bigot than a handsome young corpse.
我寧願種族歧視也不想死
Now, no offense, Detective,
我沒別的意思
but l'm just trying to keep them away from us.
我只是不想讓警察被壞人殺死
Now, what do you say we just get these people safely out of the bank?
咱們把人質安全救出來吧
l hear that.
說的好
And l'll try and watch what l say in the future.
我下次說話會小心點
You never know who's listening.
誰曉得誰會在聽
MlTCHELL: What are you doing?
你在幹嘛？
Jesus. Shit.
可惡
They bugged us.
他們在竊聽我們
Darius!
戴隊長
Darius, don't make a move!
戴隊長，停止行動！
-What? -It's all fucked up!
-什麼？ -這是圈套
Do not make a move! Keep your men back!
不能攻堅，把你的手下叫回來
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼？
They heard everything we said in the M.C.C.
我們說什麼他們都聽到
-What? -Stand down! Stand down!
-什麼？ -撤退！撤退！
The drawer with the demands in it! They heard everything we said!
對方送來的告示板 裡面裝了竊聽器
They put a transmitter in it! They bugged us!
我們說什麼都被他們聽見
No, no, no. I'm going in.
不行，我們要攻進去
Shit.
該死
Get everyone together.
把大家找來
STEVlE: Steve! Steve-O!
史蒂夫！史蒂佛！
They're coming in.
他們要攻進來
-Everybody good? -Yeah.
-準備好了嗎？ -好了
All right! Everybody out!
好了，大家出去
-Put your masks on! -Everyone out! Out!
-把面罩戴上 -大家出去！出去！
-Go now! -Go!
-去
Go! Go! Go!
出去！
-STEVE: Now! -STEVE-O: Get the fuck out!
-現在 -快給我出去
Move!
快點！
DALTON: Everybody up the fucking stairs!
大家上樓梯，快點！
-Don't shoot! Don't shoot! -Don't shoot!
-別開槍！
-Get down! Get down on the ground!
-趴下來
Cease fire!
停火！
Cease fire! Cease fire!
停火！停火！
Let's go, people.
走吧
Put your hands on your head! Get down!
趴下來，手放頭上！
Put your hands on your head.
手放頭上
-Will somebody stop him? -Get down!
-誰能阻止他？ -趴下來！
Put your hands on your head.
手放頭上
-Put your hands on your head. -Get them down!
-手放頭上 -趴下來
-On the ground! -Put your hands on your fucking heads!
-趴在地上！ -手放頭上！
Do not move!
別動！
-Get down, put your hands on your head! -Put the cuffs on them! Let's go!
-趴下來，手放頭上！ -幫他們戴上手銬！走吧！
What's going on?
搞什麼？
DARlUS: Don't take any chances!
別想逃！
lt wasn't me! l'm not a criminal!
不是我，我不是壞人
Cuffs!
手銬！
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
別開槍！
-Don't move! -l'm not moving!
-別動！ -我沒在動！
Check them. Make sure they ain't got no weapons on them and shit.
好好檢查，確定他們身上沒有武器
DARlUS: Hernandez! HERNANDEZ: Right here.
-小何 -我在這兒
HERNANDEZ: E.S.U. team, line up!
霹靂小組，集合
Door to the left, door to the left.
左邊，左邊
-Clear on the right. -Clear!
-右邊安全 -安全
-Left side clear.
-左邊安全
-All clear! -HERNANDEZ: Check under the desk.
-一切安全 -檢查桌底
-Clear. -Checking the office. All clear, Sarge.
-安全 -檢查辦公室，一切安全
Clear.
安全
All clear, Sarge.
一切安全
HERNANDEZ: All clear. E.S.U. on the stairs. Line it up!
安全，大家集合
HERNANDEZ: Let's go, guys. Team in, team in. Let's go.
去吧，快去！
Clear!
安全
-Clear.
-安全
HERNANDEZ: Give me a bunker up here. l need a bunker up front.
盾牌，我要盾牌
COP 1 : Bringing the bunker up.
把盾牌拿來
COP 2: Clear, Sarge.
安全
-We're almost clear down here. -Make sure you're sure.
-正在清除現場 -確定沒有嫌犯
-l'll keep looking. -Stay on it.
-我正在搜查 -繼續搜
Roger that.
收到
Ready? Let's go.
好了嗎？走吧
This is the last door.
最後一道門
-Clear, Sarge! -Come on down.
-安全 -下來吧
-FRAZlER: Did you find a dead hostage? -Negative.
-找到死人質嗎？ -沒有
DARlUS: lf it ain't here, you must've missed something.
一定有哪裡沒搜到
Maybe, but l'm pretty sure we're the only ones moving around down here.
不過我確定這裡只有我們
Check this out. They forgot to rob the joint.
你看，他們忘了搶錢了
MlTCHELL: Holy shit. FRAZlER: And you didn't find anybody?
-我靠 -找不到搶匪？
We're still looking, but there are no bad guys,
我們還在找，不過沒有壞人
no booby traps, no tunnels, no damage.
沒有炸彈、沒有隧道、沒有破壞
-And nothing missing. -Great, great, great.
-也沒有搶劫 -棒呆了
We'll put out a city-wide description for David fucking Copperfield, then, huh?
我們乾脆通緝大衛魔術師吧
Listen, l'm not trying to tell you your jobs, Detectives,
我想你們也應該清楚
but unless they swam out through the toilets,
除非搶匪能飛天遁地
whoever did this is upstairs sucking pavement.
不然他們就在人質之中
All right, good job.
很好
What's that?
這是什麼？
Cell phones.
手機
-Hey, guys! You need to see this. -Okay.
-大夥兒，過來看 -好
Collins! Grab a uniform, make a quick count of that money in there, all right?
柯巡警，找巡警點算鈔票
-Yes, sir. -And stand by, all right?
-是 -你在旁監督
Don't let anybody get tempted, including you!
別偷錢，包括你在內
COLLlNS: Yes, sir!
是，長官
Right here, Detective.
這裡
-What do you got? -You're going to love this one. Toy guns.
-找到什麼？ -你一定會喜歡，玩具槍
Fake guns. You got to be kidding me.
開什麼玩笑
-Toys. -As if it wasn't weird enough already.
-玩具槍 -越來越詭異了
COP: (OVER RADlO) Cap, come to the ladies' room.
隊長，請到女廁
On my way.
馬上來
Check it out.
你們看
We can stop looking for that body.
不必找屍體了
Fake guns.
假槍
Fake execution.
假裝殺人
Nobody goes home till we get everybody's story.
仔細盤問每個人質
Cap, we got something else in the storage room.
儲藏室有東西
-Porcario? -Yo.
-波卡？ -有
-Where's the men's room? -Down the hallway on the left.
-男廁在哪裡？ -走廊盡頭左手邊
COP: Pick them up, pick them up. Toss them.
把他們帶上車
MALE HOSTAGE: l'm a hostage. Stop pushing.
我是人質！別推我！
COLLlNS: Female hostages to be searched by female officers only!
只有女警才能幫女人質搜身
COP: All right, listen, let's get these people up.
把這些人帶走
-l can't hear you. What? -Valerie Keepsake.
-我聽不見，什麼？ -薇洛莉齊普賽
Valerie Keepsake. Go, go, get on the bus.
上車
-Kenneth Damerjian. -Yeah.
-肯尼德莫吉 -對
Person one.
第一個人
-l'm Peter Hammond. -Eric Dodge.
-我是彼得韓蒙 -艾瑞克道奇
-Wait! -Chaim. My name's Chaim.
-等等 -凱姆，我叫凱姆
Fucking cocksucker.
臭條子
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
等等
Just give me your name.
告訴我你的名字
Say your name.
說出你的名字
l work in the bank!
我在銀行上班
l'm the bank security guard! Nobody's listening!
我是銀行警衛，沒有人在聽我說話！
Okay, we'll straighten it out.
我們會調查的
Everybody's saying listen! Nobody's listening!
說要聽結果沒人聽！
We'll straighten it out. Come on.
我們會調查的，來吧
-Listen, l'm not getting on the bus! -Yes, you are.
-我不要上車！ -不行
-COLLlNS: Move! Move! Move! -l am not! l work at the bank!
-走！ -我在銀行上班！
COP: Collins, you got this?
你聽到嗎？
Listen, l work at the bank!
我在銀行上班
COLLlNS: All right, just get him on the bus. Get him on the bus.
把他帶上車
-Nobody's listening! -All right. Calm down. Get on the bus.
-沒人聽我說話！ -冷靜一點，上車吧
-COP 1 : Come on, guys, guys! -COP 2: Over this way. Over this way.
-走吧 -這邊
Officer, take her over to Sarge. Come on.
把她帶去給警官
COP 3: Come on, let's get going with these people off that line over there.
走吧，去搞定在那邊排隊的人
Come on.
快點
Captain, l'm telling you, this thing is a mess.
整件事一片混亂
They thought this one out, soup to nuts.
對方從頭到尾都計劃周詳
So, lay it out for me.
把事情給我交代清楚
We photograph everybody that came out of the bank.
我們拍下每個人質的照片
We sit them down, we question them, we show them the photos.
仔細盤問他們，把照片給他們看
Most of them can't point to anybody that's guilty of anything.
多半都指認不出搶匪
We ask them if they could recognize anybody who was not one of the bad guys.
我們也問他們誰不是搶匪
Even if we considered someone as a possible suspect,
就算其中有幾個可能是嫌犯
there's one or two or three other people that would rule them out.
也有兩、三人將他們排除在外
lt's like the thing never happened.
好像這件事從沒發生
-What about prints? -Everywhere. So what?
-指紋呢？ -到處都是，又怎樣？
-All it shows is that these people were there. -Alibis?
-只能證明那裡有很多人 -不在場證明？
Just about everyone.
每個人都有
Even if their alibi was weak,
就算有可疑人士
a hostage would identify them as being one of the good guys.
人質也會證明他們是好人
There we are, back to square one.
一點進展也沒有
Priors?
前科犯？
We got one employee who had some juvie stuff. One customer had...
一名職員待過少年感化院
Excuse me.
抱歉
One customer had an out-of-state warrant for child support.
一位客人沒付孩子撫養金被別州通緝
Another one had a couple of priors, G.L.A. mostly.
另一個有竊盜前科
Again, same problem. Plus, he was a fucking idiot.
一樣沒證據，而且他是笨蛋
-Bank cameras? -Useless.
-監視攝影機？ -沒有用
l'm telling you, they thought of everything. Almost.
他們幾乎什麼都想到了
-Sounded like everything to me. -But this.
-應該是全都想到了吧 -除了這個
We haven't found that .357 or the perp that was holding it.
找不到手槍和持槍的搶匪
lf you did, there'd be no prints on it anyway.
就算找到也採不到指紋
-Bury it. -Bury it?
-就這樣結案吧 -結案？
What the fuck do you expect me to say?
你要我說什麼？
Captain, this thing stinks to high hell. l mean, somebody did something here.
這起案子疑雲重重
You said it yourself.
你自己也說
You got no robbery. No suspects.
沒有搶案、沒有嫌犯
Nobody's breathing down my neck to come up with answers.
上頭也沒逼我破案
l'm not gonna breathe down yours. Bury it.
結案吧
l wasn't expecting this.
我沒猜到會這樣
l promise you, l'll find you guys more cases to solve.
我保證會讓你們辦別的案子
Okay.
好
Oh, here's something that you probably did expect.
你大概早就猜到這件事
-They found that missing Madrugada money. -No shit.
-他們找到遺失的支票 -真的假的？
Yes, you want to know where it was?
真的，你想知道在哪兒嗎？
-ln my bank account? -No.
-我的銀行帳戶？ -不是
-My summer house in Sag Harbor?
-我在山上的別墅？
-My wallet? -No.
-我的皮夾？ -也不是
Then, no. l don't want to know.
那我就不想知道
MlTCHELL: This is bullshit, man.
這太扯了
l mean, we're the only ones left trying to catch the bad guys
我們只想抓到壞人
and they're gonna come after us like that?
他們卻要整我們
l'll tell you what. Every one of your accusers, man,
誰敢找你碴
l say we go after them all, Keith, Michael Corleone style.
咱們就報仇，像教父那樣趕盡殺絕
''Michael Corleone, do you renounce Satan?''
「你唾棄撒旦嗎？」
''Yes, l renounce him.''
「我唾棄撒旦」
FRAZlER: There's no 392.
沒有392號
-Huh? -Safety deposit box number 392.
-什麼？ -392號保險箱
According to these records, it doesn't exist.
根據記錄它不存在
Pinstriped, mayonnaise, lying motherfucker.
那個臭女人當面撒謊
-Didn't Coughlin say we should move on? -Let's go.
-隊長叫我們不要查下去 -走吧
Thank you, again, Your Honor. l'll come pick it up tomorrow?
謝了，法官大人，我明天來拿
-Yes, you're welcome. -Thank you.
-沒問題 -謝謝
What are you doing, Detective?
你好
Now, what business do you have with Judge Pasqua?
你找巴法官有什麼事？
Police business.
我在辦案
-Weren't you told to bury this? -l got a job to do, Miss White.
-你不是被要求結案嗎？ -這案子我要辦到底
And since when is your job more important than your career?
曾幾何時你的案子比你的飯碗重要
-Or did you forget our arrangement? -We didn't have any arrangement.
-你忘了我們的協議嗎？ -我們沒有協議
Let me tell you how this works. You...
讓我告訴你
No, let me tell you how this works.
不，讓我告訴你
You press here to record and you press here to play.
按這裡錄音，按這裡播放
MADELElNE: (OVER RECORDER) There's also the matter of the $140,000
你負責偵辦的販毒案
from the Madrugada check-cashing bust.
有一張14萬支票不翼而飛
FRAZlER: I didn't have anything to do with that, so...
那件事與我無關
MAYOR: We'd like to be in your corner on that.
我們願意替你說好話
In exchange for what? I mean, what, do you want me to do something unethical?
你們要我犯法嗎？
I mean, no disrespect to the both of youse
我不是瞧不起你們
but I don't need you to be in my corner, Mr. Mayor.
但是我不需要市長幫忙
Look, I'm innocent.
我是無辜的
MADELElNE: Innocent or guilty, you're still going down.
不管怎樣你都會被整得很慘
MAYOR: Give Miss White whatever she needs, or your career is over.
乖乖和魏小姐合作 不然就別想在警界混下去
Done.
你玩完了
Kaput.
全完了
So? You gave me what l wanted.
你只要跟我合作
Your career is blossoming and all is right with the world.
就會飛黃騰達
What was Case hiding?
寇先生想隱瞞什麼？
You know, there's a famous saying by the Baron de Rothschild.
羅士柴爾德男爵有句名言…
''When there's blood on the streets, buy property.''
「只要街頭喋血，就開始投資」
l think Mr. Case really took that sentiment to heart.
寇先生對這點深信不疑
But he is no different than half the Fortune 500.
他和五百大企業老闆沒兩樣
Let it go, Detective.
罷手吧
You're a good cop.
你是好警察
This city needs you.
人民需要你
-Lady! Lady, you're in the wrong place. -l have an appointment.
-小姐，這是男廁 -我約了人
Arthur.
亞瑟
-Good morning. -Miss White.
-早安 -魏小姐
Have a seat.
請坐
Thank you, Vincent. That's all for now. Thank you.
謝謝你，可以了
Well. What did he say?
他怎麼說？
Well, Detective Frazier turned out to be quite sharp.
費警探很聰明
But l just fast-tracked his career a little and he's under control.
我答應讓他陞官，把他搞定了
l hope so. Tell me about the envelope.
希望如此，那個信封
Where is it now?
它在哪裡？
Well, the gang leader is going to hang on to it,
它在搶匪首領手上
as an insurance policy to keep you from seeking revenge.
以免你向他報復
Clearly, he has a very low opinion of you.
他抓住了你的把柄
And what might that be?
什麼把柄？
Well, let's see. ln a nutshell, that you got rich,
你在二次大戰大屠殺期間
doing business with the Nazis during the Holocaust.
和納粹黨做生意發大財
Yes.
對
lt was 60 years ago. l was young and ambitious.
那是六十年前的事 我很年輕，野心勃勃
l saw a short path to success and l took it.
我走上成功的捷徑
l sold my soul.
我出賣了靈魂
And l've been trying to buy it back ever since.
從此就一直想贖罪
But you and this mystery man, you have an understanding?
你和對方達到共識嗎？
l think so. And he managed to get out of there with that envelope.
應該有，他把信封帶出去
lf someday he comes back to blackmail you, well,
有一天他會勒索你
you'll pay him. And you'll get it back.
你會付錢把信封拿回來
-So, l guess that's it. -l suppose so.
-就這麼簡單 -我猜也是
-Bullshit. -l beg your pardon?
-放屁 -你說什麼？
He didn't go through all that just to stick your envelope under his mattress.
他大費周章不是為了你的信封
Look, they left money untouched, Arthur.
他們一毛錢都沒拿
So?
又怎樣？
So, he had to have walked out of there with something else.
他一定有拿走什麼
The bank says that there was nothing missing.
銀行說什麼都沒被拿走
So, there had to have been something in that box
你的保險箱
that was worth more to him than your envelope.
一定有更值錢的東西
You don't have to tell me.
你不必告訴我
There's only one thing it could be anyway.
不過只有一個可能
Diamonds.
鑽石
And then there's the ring.
還有一隻
Cartier ring.
卡地亞鑽戒
lt belonged to the wife of a Parisian banker.
它屬於一位巴黎銀行家夫人
Wealthy family of French Jews.
有錢的法國猶太家族
And when the war came along, the ring and everything else they owned
戰爭爆發後，他們的財產被納粹沒收
was confiscated and they were shipped off to concentration camps. None survived.
全家被送到集中營，無一倖免
We were friends.
我們是朋友
l could have helped them.
我可以幫助他們
But the Nazis paid too well.
但是納粹黨給的條件太好
Can l trust that you will keep what you've learned
我能信任你會對這件事
here today confidential?
守口如瓶嗎？
Despite whatever you may think?
不管你怎麼想
Yes, Arthur.
沒問題
Well, l'd love to tell you what a monster you are,
我也很想罵你是個人渣
but l have to help bin Laden's nephew buy a co-op on Park Avenue.
不過我要替本拉登的侄子買公寓
lf that were true, you wouldn't tell me.
如果是真的你就不會告訴我
We're listing you as a reference.
我會把你列為他的擔保人
My name is Dalton Russell.
我的名字是道頓羅素
Pay strict attention to what l say
請仔細聽我說的話
because l choose my words carefully and l never repeat myself.
因為我要說的話很重要 而且不會重覆一次
I've told you my name. That's the ''who. ''
我說出了名字，那是我的身份
The ''where'' could most readily be described as a prison cell.
我在的地方可以形容為囚房
But there is a vast difference
但是被困在一個小囚房
between being stuck in a tiny cell and being in prison.
和坐牢有很大的不同
The ''what'' is easy.
我做了什麼事很容易解釋
Recently I planned and set in motion events to execute the perfect bank robbery.
最近我策劃並執行一起 完美的銀行搶案
That's also the ''when.''
我也說出了時間
As for the ''why, '' beyond the obvious financial motivation,
至於為什麼，除了很明顯的財務動機
it's exceedingly simple.
原因其實非常簡單
Because I can.
因為我辦得到
Which leaves us only with the ''how. ''
現在只剩下我是怎麼辦到的
And therein, as the Bard would tell us,
就像大文豪莎士比亞說的
lies the rub.
這就耐人尋味了
STEVE: He's gonna smell like shit. STEVE-O: What do you expect after a week?
-他一定會臭得要命 -一星期沒洗澡當然會臭
CHAlM: Yeah.
是啊
Why do you think l rolled down the window?
所以我才搖下車窗
Oh, shit.
糟糕
That cop, Frazier, and his partner are walking into the bank.
費警探和他的搭檔走進銀行
-Are they coming for me? -Can't say. It's just the two of them.
-他們來找我嗎？ -不確定，只有他們倆
MAN: Yeah, everything's going great today. No.
一切都沒事
Yeah, about 5:30. Okay.
對，五點半
Sounds like fun. Okay.
聽起來很好玩
Talk to you later.
待會再聊
-Sorry. -Excuse me.
-對不起 -抱歉
Mr. Hammond?
韓先生？
Good morning, Detectives.
早安，警探
Just like he planned.
完全按照他的計劃
l got a court order here to open a safe deposit box.
我有搜票打開保險箱
Number 392.
392號保險箱
STEVE-O: Oh, thank God.
謝天謝地
Where is it?
在哪裡？
l left it in there.
我留下來了
This way, Detectives.
這裡請
Why did you do that? You left the ring.
你把鑽戒留給誰？
Trust me.
相信我
l left it in good hands.
對方很可靠
DALTON: I'm no martyr.
我不是烈士
I did it for the money.
我是為了錢
But it's not worth much if you can't face yourself in the mirror.
不過我也要對得起自己的良心
Respect is the ultimate currency.
良知比金錢更重要
I was stealing from a man who traded his away for a few dollars.
我偷一個沒有良知的人的錢
And then he tried to wash away his guilt.
他想用金錢洗清罪惡
Drown it in a lifetime of good deeds and a sea of respectability.
靠做善事獲得尊重
-Let me get that. -Let me.
-讓我來 -我自己來
It almost worked, too.
他也幾乎成功了
Okay.
好吧
But inevitably,
然而
the further you run from your sins,
你愈想逃避充滿罪惡的過去
the more exhausted you are when they catch up to you.
過去總有一天會追上來
And they do.
讓你自食其果
Son of a bitch.
好小子
Certain.
一定會
It will not fail.
這是不變的真理
FRAZlER: What do you think that's worth?
你猜這值多少錢？
(CHUCKLlNG) lf you got to ask, man, you can't afford it.
你問我，你絕對買不起
Thank goodness my girlfriend ain't here.
幸好我女朋友不在
''Follow the ring''?
「跟著鑽戒走？」
-Detective Frazier. -Mr. Case.
-費警探 -寇先生
-How are you? -l am great.
-你好嗎？ -好得很
Nobody got killed at the bank. Everybody's happy. My kind of day.
銀行沒死人，皆大歡喜，我超爽的
That's wonderful. Wonderful.
太好了
-Detective Mitchell. -Mr. Case.
-米警探 -寇先生
-Be seated, gentlemen. -Thank you.
-兩位請坐 -謝謝你
-Can l offer you anything? -No.
-喝點什麼嗎？ -不了
l must say
老實說
l was most impressed
我很佩服
by the way you handled that business.
你們處理這件事的方法
Thank you, Mr. Case.
謝謝誇獎
Whenever l hear the term ''New York's Finest''
你們真的是
you're who l think of.
人民保母
You keep the rest of us safe and make it look easy.
保護平民老百姓的安全
-Pardon me. -Well, what's so amusing?
-不好意思 -有什麼好笑？
When you say ''the rest of us,'' Mr. Case, l mean, you got to look around.
你說平民老百姓，看看你自己
''The rest of us'' is a category that you haven't qualified for in a long time.
你應該不算是平民老百姓吧
Touche, Detective. l won't deny it. l've done well.
說的好，我的確很成功
Yes, you have. But l'm very confused.
沒錯，不過我搞不懂
You see, l got a case
這件案子
where armed robbers laid siege to your bank.
搶匪佔據你的銀行
lt is your bank, right?
那是你的銀行，對吧？
Well, l'm Chairman of the Board of Directors.
我是銀行董事長
Then ita-zita-vene-gazoo.
然後…
The robbers disappear. Poof.
搶匪從人間蒸發
And they don't take a nickel, right?
一毛錢都沒拿走
-You're asking me? -Yes, l'm asking you.
-你在問我？ -對，我在問你
l mean, it's your bank. You own it. l'm asking you.
這是你的銀行，我當然要問你
lt's a tiny part of our organization.
那只是我的企業的一小部份
No robbers. No real victims. No loot missing.
沒有搶案、沒有受害者 也沒有丟掉一毛錢
lt's got to be the first time in law-enforcement history.
這一定是史上頭一遭
l never heard of it before.
我沒聽過這種怪事
So, you got to ask yourself, ''What the fuck happened?'' Don't you, Mr. Case?
你一定會想，這是怎麼回事？ 對不對？
l'm not quite sure l like your tone, Officer.
我不喜歡你的語氣
You don't like my tone? Then give me a straight answer.
不喜歡的話就說實話
lt's the founding bank of your empire. You built it. lt's your baby.
那是你開的第一家銀行 也是你的心血結晶
Give me a straight answer. What do you think happened?
老實說，發生什麼事？
-l have no idea. -Oh, come on, now. Come on.
-我不知道 -少來這一套
l'll tell you what l think happened.
讓我告訴你吧
l think you sent that woman in there to patch things up.
你派那個女人搞定一件事
Miss White. l think you paid her. What was she doing in there?
你付錢請魏小姐辦事 她替你辦什麼事？
Look, this is absurd.
這太荒謬了
Are you implying that l had anything to do with it?
你在暗示我和搶案有關？
Safe deposit box 392. What's the story on that?
392號保險箱是怎麼回事？
-l have no idea what you're... -Don't lie to me, Mr. Case.
-我不知道你在說什麼？ -別想騙我
-l don't lie. -l looked at all the records.
-我沒有說謊 -我查過所有記錄
All the bank records for safe deposit boxes at your bank.
銀行的每一個保險箱記錄
At first glance, everything looked fine,
乍看之下沒有問題
but there was one safe deposit box that had no records.
但是有一個保險箱沒有記錄
l mean, going all the way back to 1948.
從1948年起就沒有記錄
So l started thinking. Who would have the answer to this riddle?
我在想誰能解開這個謎？
Probably the man who forgot to mention
一定是1948年
that he built the bank in the first place in 1948.
成立銀行的人
lt doesn't add up, Mr. Case. lt does not add up.
這整件事都不對勁
l'm afraid l can't be of any further use to you, Detective.
我恐怕幫不了你的忙
lt's something really bad, isn't it?
你想隱藏一件可怕的秘密
Mr. Frazier, l have spent my whole life serving humanity.
我一輩子都為社會奉獻
You can ask anyone who knows me.
你可以問我的朋友
They'll vouch for me, and for the things that l've done.
他們都會替我說好話 我做了太多善事了
You think they'll vouch for you after l find out the truth about this ring?
我查出這只鑽戒的真相 他們還會替你說話嗎？
l don't think so.
應該不會吧
Oh, by the way, that thing you said about us being New York's finest?
你說我們是人民保母
l want you to know, we really appreciate that.
多謝誇獎
How gracious.
你真是客氣
Let's go. We're gonna follow that ring.
走吧，咱們要跟著鑽戒走
-Hey, Keith, let me see your shoe. -What?
-老兄，讓我看你的鞋子 -什麼？
-Let me see your shoe. -Why?
-讓我看你的鞋子 -為什麼？
'Cause l have never seen anybody put their foot that far up a guy's ass.
你狠狠地踩到那老傢伙的痛處
Yeah, l guess l did, didn't l?
我猜是吧
Oh, man. You cut him an ass the length of the Lincoln Tunnel.
你把他踩到無地自容
We're gonna need a traffic cop on that shit.
他巴不得想挖個洞鑽進去
Good afternoon, sir.
您好
-Do you have a reservation? -Looking for the Mayor.
-您有訂位嗎？ -我來找市長
-May l have your hat, please? -No, you cannot. Get your own.
-請把帽子給我 -不行，你自己去買
MADELElNE: They're looking to invest $4 billion over the next four years.
他們要在四年內投資四十億
And that's all in place.
資金都到位了
Sorry to interrupt you, Mr. Mayor, but there's an old American saying,
市長先生，抱歉打擾了 不過有句美國名言說…
''When there's blood on the streets, somebody's got to go to jail.''
「只要街頭喋血，就會有人坐牢」
Edwin, could you please excuse us for a minute?
請你離開一下
MAYOR: What's this about, Detective?
有什麼事？
l believe Detective Frazier is looking for some closure?
費警探想要一個圓滿結局
That's a good word. Closure.
說的好，圓滿結局
Case closed, you know what l mean?
我要結案，瞭嗎？
This is the number
這是
of the War Crimes lssues office in Washington, D.C.
華府戰爭罪調查局的名片
How'd you like to be on the front page of the New York Times?
你想登上《紐約時報》頭版嗎？
That'd be great.
棒呆了
Make sure they spell my name right, though. That's Frazier with a ''z''.
確定他們寫對我的名字，費雪
You can keep the pen.
錄音筆留著吧
You made copies?
你有拷貝嗎？
Please.
放心吧
We got to keep the real criminals off the streets, Your Honor.
我得去抓真正的罪犯
All right, well, thanks for lunch.
好了，多謝請客
War crimes, huh?
戰爭罪？
What have you got me into this time?
這次你把我扯進什麼事？
Mama?
寶貝？
-Did you bring Big Willie? -And the twins.
-你回來了 -還帶了一鳥二石
Slow down, girl.
別急
l'll get my gun off before l get my gun off, okay?
我先把槍放下再掏另一把槍
Pow, pow.
砰
-Sorry. -Excuse me.
-對不起 -抱歉
FRAZlER: Why don't you just walk out the door?
-你何不走出大門？ -我會的
I'm gonna walk out of that door when I'm good and ready.
我準備好就會大搖大擺走出去
Son of a bitch.
好傢伙
Come on, honey. The handcuffs are getting cold.
快點啦，手銬都冰了